[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, this is CS50.
大卫·马兰：好的，这是CS50。
And this is already week nine.
这已经是第九周了。
And this means this is the week where we synthesize
这意味着，这将是我们将过去几周内容整合在一起的一周
the past several weeks, from Python to SQL to HTML to CSS to JavaScript.
从 Python 到 SQL，再到 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript。
Each of those languages that we've rather looked at in isolation
我们之前分别学习了这些语言
now rather come together toward an end of just making
现在将要结合起来，最终目的是为了构建
more modern applications, be them web based or be they mobile based as well.
更现代的应用程序，无论是基于 Web 的还是基于移动端的。
So, up until now, we've been using, to serve all of the web stuff
到目前为止，我们一直在使用一个叫做 HTTP 服务器的程序，用于提供所有你所做的网页相关的东西
that you've done, this program called HTTP server.
这个程序叫做 HTTP 服务器。
Now, this isn't a CS50 thing.
现在，这不是一个 CS50 的东西。
It's just a standard program that we've installed into Codespaces.
它只是一个标准的程序，我们把它安装到了 Codespaces 中。
So it's a Linux program that just runs your own web server.
所以它是一个 Linux 程序，可以运行你自己的 Web 服务器。
And it allows you to run it on nonstandard ports.
而且它允许你运行在非标准端口上。
For instance, you've been using it on port 80, 80
例如，你一直在端口 80 上使用它，端口 80
only because Codespaces is using 80 and 443, recall, which were the defaults.
只有因为 Codespaces 正在使用 80 和 443，还记得吗？这是默认的。
But, up until now, this program's purpose in life
但是，到目前为止，这个程序的用途
was just to serve static content, so like web pages written in HTML,
仅仅是为了提供静态内容，比如用 HTML 编写的网页，
maybe some CSS, maybe some JavaScript that you wrote in advance
可能还有一些 CSS，可能还有一些你提前写好的 JavaScript
that just never really changes until such time
这些代码在一段时间内都不会改变，直到
as you log back into the server, save the file after making some edits,
你重新登录服务器，在进行了一些编辑之后保存文件，
and then someone reloads their page.
然后有人重新加载他们的页面。
But, of course, the web that we all use today, be it Gmail or any website,
但当然，我们今天使用的互联网，无论是 Gmail 还是任何网站，
is so much more interactive.
都要交互得多。
When you search for something on Google, there's
当你搜索谷歌上的东西时，
no Google engineer that, in advance, has written up an HTML
没有谷歌工程师提前写好了一个 HTML
page containing a list of 10 cats or 10 dogs
页面，其中包含 10 只猫或 10 只狗
or 10 birds just waiting for someone to search for that particular keyword.
或者 10 只鸟，只是等着有人搜索那个特定的关键词。
Rather, there's some database involved.
而是涉及到了数据库。
The HTML's being dynamically generated.
HTML 代码正在动态生成。
And it's all indeed very dynamic.
而且这确实非常动态。
So whereas, last week, we focused on websites,
所以，在上周，我们关注的是网站，
this week we'll focus really on web applications.
这周我们将重点关注 Web 应用程序。
And, really, the key difference is just that applications
实际上，关键的区别在于应用程序
take input and produce output whereas websites are really generally thought
接收输入并产生输出，而网站通常被认为是
of as static.
静态的。
But it's a blurry line.
但这只是一条模糊的界线。
It's not necessarily a technical distinction.
这不是一个技术上的区别。
But today things start to get much more interactive.
但今天的事情会变得更加交互式。
So we're not going to be able to use HTTP server alone.
所以我们不能只使用 HTTP 服务器。
We're going to need something a little smarter that knows how
我们需要一些更智能的东西，它知道如何
to take input from users via the URL.
通过 URL 从用户那里获取输入。
So, in fact, let's look at some sample URLs that we looked at last week
实际上，让我们看看上周我们看过的几个示例 URL
just to remind ourselves of some of the jargon and really the syntax.
来提醒我们一些术语和语法。
So here's a standard URL and Flask, recall,
这是一个标准的 URL，还记得 Flask 吗？
is just the default page on the server.
它只是服务器上的默认页面。
And, usually, the file is called index.html by convention.
通常，按照惯例，这个文件叫做 index.html。
But, depending on the operating system or web server you're using,
但是，这取决于你使用的操作系统或 Web 服务器，
it could be a different file.
它可能是一个不同的文件。
But index.html is probably the most common default.
但 index.html 可能是最常见的默认选项。
So you could explicitly state the file name on most web servers
所以你可以在大多数 Web 服务器上显式地声明文件名
like file.html, index.html, whatever it is.
比如 file.html、index.html，无论是什么。
You can have folders or directories on a web server.
你可以在 Web 服务器上创建文件夹或目录。
And this would imply that your index.html file is
这将意味着你的 index.html 文件
in a folder called folder in this case.
在这种情况下，它位于一个名为“folder”的文件夹中。
Or you can have a folder/file or even folder/folder/folder/file and so forth.
或者你可以创建 folder/file，甚至 folder/folder/folder/file 等等。
So this is a very direct mapping from the URL to the file system,
所以这是一个从 URL 到文件系统的直接映射，
so to speak, like the hard drive on the server.
可以这样说，就像服务器上的硬盘驱动器。
But, today, we're going to do, like most computer scientists tend to do,
但是，今天，我们将会做一些像大多数计算机科学家通常会做的事情，
is more of an abstraction of this.
进行抽象。
This is how URLs look.
这就是 URL 的样子。
But it turns out, once you control the web server with code,
但事实证明，一旦你用代码控制了 Web 服务器，
you don't need things to line up with actual file names and files.
你就不需要将它们与实际的文件名和文件对齐。
You can really put your content wherever you want.
你可以把你想要的内容放在任何地方。
And so, in general, we're going to focus today
所以，一般来说，我们今天将重点关注
on just thinking of everything after the domain name as a path,
将域名之后的所有内容都视为路径，
generally speaking.
一般而言。
And a synonym for this, in the context of the web, would also just be a route.
在 Web 上下文中，这个词的同义词就是路由。
So a route is just some number of letters, maybe some slashes, maybe
所以路由只是一些字母，可能有一些斜杠，可能
a file extension that refers to some part of your application.
一个文件扩展名，它指的是应用程序的某一部分。
But, more interestingly-- and this is what makes things an application
但更有趣的是——这也是让一些东西成为应用程序而不是静态网站的原因——
and not just a static website--
它不仅仅是一个静态网站——
recall, that this is how websites can take input
还记得吗，这就是网站可以接收输入的方式
in the form of URLs, a question mark, then key equals value pair.
通过 URL 的形式，一个问号，然后是键值对。
Or if you want two or maybe three or four,
或者如果你想要两个、三个或四个，
you separate them with ampersands.
你用“&”符号将它们分隔开。
But that's kind of it.
但就是这样了。
The web today is going to work just like it did last week,
今天的互联网将像上周一样工作，
but we're going to start leveraging these primitives in a much
但我们将开始以一种更加强大、更加交互的方式利用这些基本元素。
more powerful, more interactive way.
更加强大、更加交互的方式。
So here, recall, is what might be inside of the virtual envelope
所以，回想一下，当你在谷歌上搜索东西的时候，虚拟信封里可能会是什么。
when you search for something on google.com.
当你搜索 google.com 上的东西的时候。
It's going to request of the web server/search, which
它将请求 Web 服务器/搜索，它
is the name, by convention, of Google's search application
是谷歌搜索应用程序的名称，按照惯例，
because they've got a lot of businesses running on their servers.
因为他们的服务器上运行着许多业务。
And if you have ?q=cats, this is essentially the message,
如果你有 ?q=cats，这本质上就是消息，
the HTTP message that would've been in last week's virtual envelope when I
上周我在搜索猫的时候，这个 HTTP 消息就在虚拟信封里。
searched for cats.
搜索猫。
Hopefully, you get back a response from the server
希望你能从服务器那里得到一个包含这些猫的响应。
containing those actual cats.
包含这些猫的响应。
But, again, there's probably a lot more logic going on with a database
但是，再说一次，很可能还涉及到更多的数据库逻辑
and somehow generating that HTML that Google is doing for us.
以及谷歌如何为我们生成那个 HTML。
So we, today, are going to introduce really
所以，今天，我们将介绍真正
what's called a framework or technically a microframework, which
被称为框架，或者更准确地说是微框架，
means it's relatively small versus alternatives that are out there.
这意味着它相对于市面上的其他替代方案来说比较小。
And it's called Flask.
它被称为 Flask。
So Flask is really a third-party library--
所以 Flask 实际上是一个第三方库——
and it's popular in the Python world-- that's
它在 Python 世界中很受欢迎——这是
just going to make it easier to implement web applications using
仅仅是为了让使用
Python.
Python 来实现 Web 应用程序变得更容易。
There are alternatives.
还有其他选择。
A very popular one is called Django, which some of you
一个非常流行的选择叫做 Django，你们中有些人
might've heard of before.
可能之前听说过它。
And there's dozens of others in decreasing popularity daresay.
还有数十个其他的，受欢迎程度逐渐下降。
But Flask is among the most popular microframeworks,
但 Flask 是最流行的微框架之一，
which means you can really just solve a few problems pretty
这意味着你实际上可以非常简单地解决一些问题，
simply without feeling like you're learning some third-party library
而不必担心自己是在学习一些第三方库，
as much as you are learning concepts that transcend
你是在学习一些超越
one particular implementation.
特定实现的观念。
So we're going to introduce you to a framework called Flask.
所以我们将会向你介绍一个叫做 Flask 的框架。
And that's going to allow us, ultimately,
这将最终使我们能够
to start web applications not by running HTTP server today
启动 Web 应用程序，不再需要像今天一样运行 HTTP 服务器，
but literally running flask space run.
而是直接运行 "flask run"。
So this framework literally gives you a command,
因此这个框架实际上为你提供了一个命令，
on your Mac, your PC, your codespace once it's installed,
在你的 Mac、PC 或者你的 Codespace 中，一旦它安装完毕，
that allows you to start a web server by running
你就可以通过运行这个命令来启动一个 Web 服务器，
flask run instead of HTTP server.
运行 "flask run"，而不是 "HTTP server"。
So, again, last week, it was all about static websites.
所以，再次强调，上周我们谈论的都是静态网站。
This week, it's all about dynamic websites instead.
而这周，我们将会谈论动态网站。
And, by framework, we really generally mean-- not just
而说到框架，我们通常指的是——不仅仅是
using some third-party code but third-party conventions
使用一些第三方代码，而是第三方约定，
that just some human or humans decided is the way
一些人或一些人决定了构建应用程序的方式。
you will build your applications.
这就是你构建应用程序的方式。
Usually, this is just based on lessons learned after making application
通常，这只是基于在开发应用程序后获得的经验教训。
after application.
开发一个又一个应用程序。
Humans around the internet realized, you know what?
互联网上的人们意识到，你知道吗？
We should probably standardize the names of our files, the names of our folders,
我们可能应该将文件名称、文件夹名称以及
and how things are laid out.
文件组织方式进行标准化。
And so, even though this is not the only way to do things,
因此，虽然这不是唯一的方式，
the way that Flask prescribes that we programmers do things is this.
Flask 规定我们程序员做事的方式是这样的。
We'll, starting today, always have a Python program called app.py
从今天开始，我们总是会有一个叫做 app.py 的 Python 程序，
by convention, like in our folder.
按照惯例，就像在我们的文件夹中一样。
And we're going to have a folder called templates, inside of which
我们还会有一个叫做 templates 的文件夹，其中包含
is any of the actual HTML, maybe CSS, maybe JavaScript that we write.
我们编写的任何实际的 HTML，可能是 CSS，可能是 JavaScript。
But you can actually put some of that content elsewhere.
但你实际上可以把一些内容放在其他地方。
And, in fact, you'll see there's going to be generally
事实上，你会发现通常
two other files or folders you'll see me create or me use today.
你还会看到我今天创建或使用的另外两个文件或文件夹。
One is called requirements.txt, which is literally just a simple text
一个是叫做 requirements.txt 的文件，它实际上只是一个简单的文本
file wherein you specify one per line what third-party libraries
文件，你可以在里面一行一行地指定你想要使用的第三方库。
you want to use.
你想要使用的库。
This file just makes it easy to install those libraries with a command.
这个文件使用一个命令来安装这些库变得很容易。
And then, lastly, a static folder.
然后，最后，还有一个静态文件夹。
And it's in this folder that you put images or .css files or .js files,
在这个文件夹中，你放置图片、CSS 文件、JS 文件，
literally files that are meant to be static that you might change them once
实际上这些文件应该是静态的，你可能偶尔会改变它们，
in a while, but they're not changing every day.
但它们不是每天都会改变。
And so you just want to isolate them to a particular folder.
所以你只需要将它们隔离到一个特定的文件夹。
Why is it this way?
为什么是这样？
Eh, a bunch of humans decided this feels like a clean solution.
嗯，一群人决定，这感觉是一个干净的解决方案。
But reasonable people will disagree and different frameworks lay things out
但是，理智的人会不同意，不同的框架会有不同的组织方式。
differently.
不同的组织方式。
So, when using a framework for the first time, you take a class or read a book
所以，当你第一次使用一个框架时，你需要参加一个课程或者阅读一本书
or read the documentation.
或者阅读文档。
And it will essentially guide you to how you should lay out your application.
它基本上会指导你如何组织你的应用程序。
So let's go ahead and do exactly that and make an application that quite
所以，让我们开始做，创建这样一个应用程序，它非常
simply and, by design, underwhelmingly implements Hello, world.
简单，而且有意地，平淡无奇地实现了 "Hello, world"。
But, rather than do this statically, let me
但是，与其静态地实现，让我
do it in a way that starts to use this framework so
使用这个框架的方式来实现，这样
that, in the next version of it, we can actually take user input
在下一个版本中，我们就可以接收用户输入
and have it say not Hello, world but maybe Hello,
并让它说，不是 "Hello, world"，而是 "Hello,
David, or Hello, Yulia or anyone else.
David"，或者 "Hello, Yulia"，或者其他任何人。
All right, so let me go over here to VS Code.
好的，让我转到 VS Code。
And let me go ahead, and, initially, let me start with the familiar.
让我继续，首先，让我从熟悉的东西开始。
And let me go ahead and start by simply creating the HTML page that I really
让我开始创建一个 HTML 页面，这个页面是我真的
want to show to my visitors when they visit my application.
想要在我应用程序的访客访问时展示给他们的。
So I'm going to go ahead and, somewhat incorrectly, initially,
所以，我先创建一个，它最初可能有点错误，
but just to make a point, I'm going to go ahead and do
但仅仅是为了说明一个问题，我先创建一个
code index.html to open up a new tab.
叫做 "index.html" 的文件，打开一个新的标签页。
I'll hide my terminal window just to give myself some more room.
为了给自己留出更多空间，我先隐藏我的终端窗口。
And then really fast I'm going to type out some boilerplate HTML.
然后，我快速地输入一些基本的 HTML 代码。
So DOCTYPE html, just like last week, open bracket html Lang equals en just
所以 "DOCTYPE html"，就像上周一样，然后是 "html Lang equals en"，
to tell the VS Code that I'm--
告诉 VS Code 我正在——
to tell the web that I'm largely using English here.
告诉网页我在这里主要使用的是英语。
In the head of my page, I'm going to have, of course, the title of the page.
在页面的 "head" 部分，我当然要包含页面的标题。
And I'll keep it simple and just say something like hello.
为了保持简洁，我就写上 "hello"。
But just so that this website actually renders nicely on mobile devices,
但为了让这个网站在移动设备上显示得很好，
I'm going to use one of those meta tags we talked briefly
我会使用上周简要提到的元标签之一，
about last week whereby if I say meta name equals viewport--
上周我们说过，如果我写 "meta name equals viewport"——
and viewport refers to just the big rectangular region of your browser--
而 "viewport" 指的是浏览器中那个大的矩形区域——
the content of this meta tag is going to be initial scale
这个元标签的内容应该是 "initial scale"
equals 1 and width equals device width.
"equals 1" 以及 "width equals device width"。
I always have to copy-paste this or look it up myself.
我总是要复制粘贴它或者自己查找它。
But this line here essentially tells the browser
但是这行代码实际上告诉浏览器，
that, no matter how wide the device is, whether it's
无论设备有多宽，无论是
a laptop or desktop or maybe a vertical cell phone or tablet,
笔记本电脑、台式电脑，还是竖着的手机或平板电脑，
size the viewport to that device.
将视窗大小调整到该设备的大小。
Otherwise, your website might look super small on mobile devices
否则，您的网站在移动设备上看起来可能非常小
if you don't use this tag to tell the browser, take into account
如果您不使用此标签来告诉浏览器，请考虑
the actual device width rather than shrinking the 12-point font
实际设备宽度，而不是缩小 12 点字体
to something that's hard for folks to read.
变成难以阅读的东西。
So, for now, I'm just going to generally copy-paste that or type it out
所以，现在，我将简单地复制粘贴它或将其键入
from my printout here.
从我的打印输出中。
All right, beyond that, we need the body of the page.
好的，除此之外，我们需要页面的主体。
We'll keep that simple.
我们会保持简单。
So body, and then, in here, hello comma world.
所以 body，然后，在里面，hello，world。
So that's it for my website thus far.
到目前为止，这就是我的网站。
It's static.
它是静态的。
Nothing about this is going to incorporate my name or anyone else's.
关于这一点，不会包含我的名字或任何其他人的名字。
So I could technically use HTTP server to serve up this web page,
所以，从技术上讲，我可以使用 HTTP 服务器来提供此网页，
open it in a browser, and I would see the actual contents.
在浏览器中打开它，我将看到实际内容。
But let's instead create a bit of work for us
但让我们改为为我们创造一些工作
and sort of overengineer this problem but to set the stage for actually
并且以某种方式过度设计这个问题，但要为实际
taking in dynamic input like a user's name.
获取动态输入，例如用户姓名。
So let me go ahead and to do this.
所以让我继续这样做。
I'm going to go ahead and open my terminal window again.
我将继续打开我的终端窗口。
I'm going to close the index.html file.
我将关闭 index.html 文件。
I'm going to make a new directory called templates,
我将创建一个名为 templates 的新目录，
which, again, was the default folder name I
它又是默认的文件夹名称，我
mentioned that this framework expects.
提到了这个框架期望的。
And I'm going to move index.html into that templates folder using mv, a Linux
我将使用 mv 命令，将 index.html 移动到该 templates 文件夹中，这是一个 Linux
command.
命令。
If you're more comfy, you can open up the file, the File Explorer at right.
如果您更喜欢，您可以打开文件，右边的文件资源管理器。
You'll see, in advance, I downloaded a directory.
你会看到，提前，我下载了一个目录。
I'll occasionally borrow content from today called src9,
我偶尔会从今天称为 src9 的内容中借用内容，
but there is my templates folder.
但那里是我的 templates 文件夹。
And you could click in the GUI in order to do
您可以单击 GUI 以执行
what I just did at the command line.
我刚刚在命令行中执行的操作。
All right, and, after this, let's go ahead and create one other file,
好的，然后，在此之后，让我们继续创建一个其他文件，
app.py.
app.py。
And, in app.py, let me go ahead now and do this.
然后，在 app.py 中，让我继续这样做。
I'm going to import some functions that come with this framework called Flask.
我将导入此框架附带的一些函数，称为 Flask。
So I'm going to say from flask, in lowercase, import Flask, capital F,
所以，我将说从 flask 中，用小写，导入 Flask，大写 F，
and also a function called render template and an object called request.
以及一个名为 render_template 的函数和一个名为 request 的对象。
Now, how to do this?
现在，如何做到这一点？
You literally read the documentation, or you listen to someone
您实际上阅读了文档，或者您听某人
like me tell you to begin your program this way.
像我一样告诉你以这种方式开始你的程序。
In the Flask framework comes three pieces of functionality
在 Flask 框架中包含三个功能
that are just useful to incorporate into my own program as we're about to see.
它们对于将它们合并到我的程序中非常有用，正如我们即将看到的。
Here's the line of code via which I can tell this framework
这是一行代码，通过它我可以告诉这个框架
to treat my file, app.py, as indeed a web application.
将我的文件 app.py 视为一个网络应用程序。
I create a variable, typically called app.
我创建一个变量，通常称为 app。
I set that equal to the return value of calling
我将其设置为调用
this Flask function and pass in it, somewhat weirdly,
这个 Flask 函数，并且将它传递进去，有点奇怪，
the name of this file.
这个文件的名字。
So this is the only weird thing for now in that we haven't used this much,
所以，目前唯一奇怪的是我们还没有使用过太多，
if at all. __name__ is a special variable in Python that literally
如果有的话。__name__ 是 Python 中的一个特殊变量，它实际上
refers to the current file's name, no matter what file name you gave it.
指的是当前文件的名字，无论你给它什么文件名。
So it's a nice way of referring to yourself
所以，这是一个很好的方法来指代自己
without manually typing the file name, which might change down the line.
无需手动键入文件名，文件名可能会发生更改。
And then, lastly, I'm going to do this.
然后，最后，我将这样做。
And this is one other piece of new syntax for now.
而这是目前另一段新的语法。
I'm going to use an @ and say app.route.
我将使用 @ 并说 app.route。
And then in quotes, as an argument to this route function,
然后用引号，作为此 route 函数的参数，
I'm going to specify the route for which I'm implementing some code
我将指定我要为其实现某些代码的路由
/ being the default, by convention.
/ 是默认值，按照惯例。
I'm going to define immediately below that a function
我将在下面立即定义一个函数
that I can technically call anything I want,
我从技术上讲可以调用任何我想要的东西，
but I'm going to get in the habit of using reasonable defaults.
但我将养成使用合理默认值的习惯。
So I'm going to call this function index by default.
所以，默认情况下，我将调用此函数 index。
But that's not a hard requirement.
但这并不是一个硬性要求。
And then, inside of this function, I'm simply
然后，在这个函数内部，我只是
going to return this, return "hello, world", quote, unquote.
将要返回它，返回 "hello, world"，引号，取消引号。
And that's it.
就这样。
This I now claim is a beginning of an actual web application.
我现在声称这是一个实际网络应用程序的开始。
It looks a little magical or cryptic as to what's going on.
看起来有点神奇或神秘，因为不知道发生了什么。
But, per the jargon I introduced earlier, this function here app.route
但是，根据我之前介绍的术语，这里 app.route 函数
is defining a route for this application that
正在为这个应用程序定义一个路由，
implies that whenever a human visit slash
这意味着每当一个人访问斜杠
on this application, what should happen is
在这个应用程序上，应该发生的是
this function index should get called.
这个 index 函数应该被调用。
And that function's purpose in life, at the moment,
而这个函数目前存在的目的，
is just to return, quote, unquote, "hello, world", and that's it.
只是返回 "hello, world"，就这样。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续这样做。
Let me open my terminal and just to keep everything
让我打开我的终端，只是为了保持一切
clean because we're going to have a bunch of applications
干净，因为我们今天将要进行很多应用程序
today in the works.
今天的作品。
I'm going to create one other folder called hello.
我将创建一个名为 hello 的其他文件夹。
And I'm going to move app.py and templates into that hello folder.
我将把 app.py 和 templates 移动到那个 hello 文件夹中。
So if I now type ls in my own personal account,
所以，如果我现在在我的个人帐户中键入 ls，
I've got that folder hello and also src9, which I brought with me today.
我有了那个名为 hello 的文件夹，还有 src9，我今天把它带了来。
So if I now cd into hello and type ls again,
所以，如果我现在 cd 到 hello 中，然后再次键入 ls，
I'll see the two things we just created together, app.py
我将看到我们刚刚一起创建的两个东西，app.py
and the templates folder.
和 templates 文件夹。
And if I go one step further in ls templates itself,
如果我再进一步在 ls templates 本身中，
I should see, of course, index.html.
我当然应该看到 index.html。
All right, so a lot of steps to go through just to get started.
好的，所以要经过很多步骤才能开始。
But you'll see that this is fairly boilerplate eventually.
但你会看到，这最终是相当标准的。
I'm not going to run an HTTP server, but I
我不会运行 HTTP 服务器，但我
am going to run flask run, which will turn this app.py into a working web
将运行 flask run，它将把这个 app.py 变成一个可工作的网络
application.
应用程序。
The output after I hit Enter is going to look a little more cryptic.
按下回车键后的输出会更难懂一些。
It's going to warn me this is a development server.
它会提醒我这是一个开发服务器。
You should not use that same command in the real world.
你不应该在现实世界中使用相同的命令。
You should actually configure Flask a little differently if you're
如果你要
going to use it in the real world.
在现实世界中使用它，你需要对 Flask 进行一些不同的配置。
But it does show me the random URL that GitHub created for me.
但它确实显示了 GitHub 为我创建的随机 URL。
And I'm going to go ahead and open this URL.
我将打开这个 URL。
It's going to open in a new tab.
它将在一个新的标签页中打开。
And, voila, that is my web application.
瞧，这就是我的网络应用程序。
Completely underwhelming, but you'll notice
完全不起眼，但你会注意到
that, even though Chrome is hiding this, this
即使 Chrome 隐藏了它，但这
is the equivalent of my having visited at the end of this URL simply a slash.
相当于我在这个 URL 的末尾访问了一个斜杠。
All right, if I zoom out here, though, and maybe right-click or Control-click,
好的，如果我在这里缩小，然后右键单击或 Control-单击，
and I choose View page source--
然后选择查看页面源代码--
recall, this is available in most every browser--
请记住，这在大多数浏览器中都是可用的--
you'll see that this isn't actually HTML because, at the moment,
你会看到，这实际上不是 HTML，因为目前
I'm literally just returning, quote, unquote, "hello, world".
我实际上只是返回了“hello, world”。
So, yes, it's text.
所以，是的，它是文本。
It's being rendered as a web page.
它被渲染成一个网页。
But it's not technically a web page that has valid HTML.
但严格来说，它不是一个包含有效 HTML 的网页。
So what I'm going to do here is this.
所以我要做的是这个。
I'm going to go back into VS Code.
我要回到 VS Code 中。
I'm going to open a second terminal by clicking
我将通过点击
the plus icon toward the bottom right of my screen,
屏幕右下角的加号图标
just so I can keep the server running.
来打开第二个终端，以便保持服务器运行。
But-- actually, nope, let me go ahead and do this.
但是--实际上，不，让我继续做这个。
Let me kill this terminal.
让我关闭这个终端。
Let me actually-- oops, I killed the wrong one.
让我实际上--哦，我关错了。
Let me instead go into my hello directory again.
让我回到我的 hello 目录。
Let me open up app.py.
让我打开 app.py。
And this time, instead of saying hello, world, let me do this.
这一次，与其说 hello, world，不如让我做这个。
I want to return the contents of index.html,
我想返回 index.html 的内容，
which is that whole file I created, but I can't just specify its file name.
也就是我创建的那个完整的文件，但我不能只指定它的文件名。
But I can do this.
但我可以这样做。
I can call a function called render_template,
我可以调用一个名为 render_template 的函数，
which comes with Flask.
它是 Flask 附带的。
And its purpose in life is to go get that file from a folder
它的作用是从一个名为
called templates, open it up and then send
templates 的文件夹中获取那个文件，打开它，然后发送
all of those bytes, all of those characters
所有这些字节，所有这些字符
to the user's actual browser.
到用户的实际浏览器。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这个。
Let me open my terminal again.
让我再次打开我的终端。
Let me do flask run inside of this same folder hello.
让我在这个名为 hello 的文件夹中运行 flask run。
I'm now going to go back to my tab here, click Reload,
我现在将回到我的标签页，单击重新加载，
and nothing appears to have changed.
看起来没有任何变化。
But if I right-click and choose View source this time after reloading,
但如果我重新加载后右键单击并选择查看源代码，
now you'll see all of the HTML that I composed.
现在你会看到我编写的所有 HTML。
All right, so this has taken way more steps
好的，所以这比上周仅仅运行 HTTP server 多了更多步骤
to do what we achieved by just running HTTP server last week.
来完成上周我们仅仅通过运行 HTTP server 就实现的功能。
But here's where now things can get a little interesting, whereby
但现在有趣的地方来了，因为
now that we have this framework laid out,
现在我们已经搭建了这个框架，
we can actually introduce other features of the framework
我们实际上可以引入框架的其他功能
to make things more dynamic.
来使事情更动态。
So, for instance, what I'm going to do is this.
例如，我要做的是这个。
I'm going to now introduce a feature of that variable
我现在要引入我导入的
that I also imported called request, which refers to any HTTP request.
那个名为 request 的变量的功能，它指的是任何 HTTP 请求。
And it turns out, there's a property inside
事实证明，里面有一个属性
of there called args, which is actually going
名为 args，它实际上是
to be a dictionary of all of the key value pairs
所有键值对的字典，
that the human might've provided via the URL.
这些键值对可能是人类通过 URL 提供的。
So I don't have to figure out, how do I find the thing after the question mark?
所以我不用再去想，如何找到问号后面的东西？
I don't have to worry about parsing the ampersands.
我不用担心解析与号。
Flask does all of that for me and just hands
Flask 为我做好了所有这些工作，并直接提供给我
me anything after the URL in a Python dictionary instead.
URL 后面的任何东西，以 Python 字典的形式。
So let me do this.
所以让我做这个。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到 VS Code。
Let me go ahead and hide the terminal.
让我隐藏一下终端。
But, in app.py, let me go ahead and make a relatively simple change.
但是，在 app.py 中，让我进行一个相对简单的更改。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续做这个。
Let me go ahead and open up in my hello folder, let me open up index.html.
让我打开我的 hello 文件夹，让我打开 index.html。
And let me go ahead and get rid of world and just put a placeholder here.
然后让我删除 world，并在这里放一个占位符。
Using curly brackets, two of them, on the left and right,
使用大括号，左右各一个，
I'm going to go ahead and plug in a variable like name.
我要插入一个名为 name 的变量。
So here's now where I'm treating index.html not as literally
所以现在我将 index.html 不再视为文字意义上的
an HTML page anymore, but more as a template in the literal sense.
HTML 页面，而是更像一个字面意义上的模板。
So a template is kind of like a blueprint whereby
所以模板就像一个蓝图，可以
you can construct most of what you want the human to see but then
构建你想让用户看到的大部分内容，但
leave little placeholders in, a la a blueprint
留下一些占位符，就像蓝图一样
where you can fill in certain blanks.
可以在某些地方填空。
The double curly quotes here is actually a feature
这里的双花括号实际上是
of technically another language-- it's not
另一种语言的功能--它不是
a programming language-- called Jinja.
一门编程语言--它叫做 Jinja。
But Jinja is simply a language that a bunch of other humans
但 Jinja 仅仅是一门语言，由许多其他人
came up with that standardizes what syntax
创造出来，用来标准化你可以使用的语法
you can use for these placeholders and some other features as well.
来使用这些占位符以及其他一些功能。
So this is going to happen more and more as you progress more
所以，随着你学习编程和计算机科学的深入，这种情况会越来越常见。
in programming and CS.
学习编程和计算机科学的深入，这种情况会越来越常见。
It's not going to be as simple as, oh, I'm implementing something in Python.
它不会像这样简单，哦，我正在用 Python 实现某些东西。
Or, oh, I'm implementing something in C. It's generally going to be,
或者，哦，我正在用 C 语言实现某些东西。通常来说，
oh, I'm implementing something with this full stack of software,
哦，我正在用这个完整的软件栈来实现某些东西，
including HTML, CSS, Python, some SQL, some Jinja, and so forth.
包括 HTML、CSS、Python、一些 SQL、一些 Jinja 等等。
So into your vocabulary is now going to generally come a list of technologies
因此，你的词汇量现在将通常包括你在解决某个问题时使用的技术列表，
that you're using when solving some problem, no
而不是单个语言。
longer individual languages.
So, by this, I just mean this.
所以，我的意思就是这个。
The Flask framework took a look around the internet and saw,
Flask 框架浏览了一下互联网，看到，
OK, the humans at the Jinja group came up
好的，Jinja 团队的人想出了
with a nice simple syntax for putting placeholders in.
一个简单易懂的语法来放置占位符。
Let's support that syntax in Flask.
让我们在 Flask 中支持这个语法。
So it's sort of one framework collaborating with another.
所以这有点像一个框架与另一个框架的合作。
So if I go back to app.py now, how do I actually pass from my application
所以，如果我现在回到 app.py，我该怎么从我的应用程序中
to that template whatever the human has typed in?
传递到模板中，无论用户输入了什么？
Well, it turns out I can go ahead and do this.
事实证明，我可以直接这么做。
Let me go ahead and in my index function, which, again,
让我继续，在我的 index 函数中，再次说明，
is what's going to get called anytime someone visits that slash route,
它是任何访问那个斜杠路由时都会调用的函数，
I'm going to go ahead and create a variable called name.
我将创建一个名为 name 的变量。
I'm going to set it equal to requests.args.
我将它设置为 requests.args。
And then I'm going to go ahead and say, how about, quote, unquote, "name".
然后我将继续说，怎样，引号，引号，"name"。
I claimed, a moment ago, that args is a dictionary that
我之前说过，args 是一个字典，它
just comes automatically with Flask and whenever
会自动和 Flask 一起提供，并且只要
a human makes a request to the server, and it
用户向服务器发出请求，它就会
puts in that dictionary all of the key value pairs from the URL.
将 URL 中的所有键值对放入这个字典中。
And the last thing I'm going to do here is this.
最后一步，我将做的是这个。
I'm going to actually say-- and, actually, just let
我要说的是，实际上，就让
me make this more explicit.
我将这个更明确一点。
Let me call this placeholder literally placeholder.
让我把这个占位符叫做 placeholder。
And what I'm going to do now is, in render template,
现在我要做的是，在渲染模板中，
I'm going to take advantage of one other feature that comes with this function.
我将利用这个函数自带的另一个特性。
It can take one or more arguments.
它可以接收一个或多个参数。
And if you pass in more, you can specify variables
如果你传递更多参数，你可以指定变量
that you want the function to have access to.
你想让函数访问的。
So I can literally do something like this, placeholder equals name.
所以，我就可以直接做这样的事情，placeholder 等于 name。
So recall that Python supports named parameters, which
请记住，Python 支持命名参数，这意味着
just means that you can pass in multiple arguments to a function.
你可以向函数传递多个参数。
But you can specify them by name.
但是你可以通过名称来指定它们。
So I am calling one of these arguments placeholder.
所以，我将其中一个参数命名为 placeholder。
And I'm setting the value of that argument
我将这个参数的值
equal to name, which itself is a variable that I
设置为 name，它本身是一个我
defined just a moment ago.
刚才定义的变量。
So, now, what's going to happen?
现在，将会发生什么？
Well, let me actually go back to my VS Code.
好吧，让我回到 VS Code。
I'm going to go ahead and run Flask as I did before.
我将继续运行 Flask，就像之前一样。
The URL is not going to change in this case,
在这种情况下，URL 不会改变，
I'm going to go back to my other tab.
我要回到我的另一个标签页。
I'm going to go ahead now and change the URL manually-- let me zoom in here--
我现在将手动更改 URL，让我放大一下，
to be /?name=David.
变成 /?name=David。
I'm not going to hit Enter yet.
我现在不会按 Enter。
Let me zoom out.
让我缩小一下。
But, when I do zoom out here, I think we should see now, hello, David.
但是，当我缩小的时候，我想我们现在应该看到，hello, David。
So here we go.
好了，就是这样。
Enter.
按 Enter。
And, voila, we see hello, David.
瞧，我们看到了 hello, David。
But, more interestingly, if I view source
但更有趣的是，如果我查看源代码
here by right-clicking or Control-clicking on the page or opening
通过右键单击或 Control 键单击页面，或者打开
developer tools and so forth and go to View page source,
开发人员工具等等，然后选择 View page source，
it appears that what the server sent to my browser
看起来，服务器发送到我的浏览器的
is literally a web page that says hello, David.
是一个包含 "hello, David" 的网页。
There is no more placeholder.
不再有占位符。
There is no more curly braces.
不再有花括号。
Literally, the content that came from the server is that string.
实际上，来自服务器的内容就是那个字符串。
And so this is the distinction now between being
所以，现在，静态应用程序和动态应用程序之间的区别就是
a static application versus dynamic.
静态应用程序和动态应用程序。
What I wrote statically was literally this index.html file.
我静态编写的是这个 index.html 文件。
But what got served dynamically is that file
但动态提供的是那个文件
plus the substitution or interpolation of that placeholder variable.
加上对那个占位符变量的替换或插值。
So we have the beginnings, it would seem, of a web application.
所以，看起来我们已经有了构建一个 Web 应用程序的雏形。
And think back to Google.
想一想 Google。
Google is essentially implemented the same way, /search?q=cats.
Google 基本上也是用同样的方式实现的，/search?q=cats。
So they're doing more with the key value pair than just spitting it back out,
所以，它们对键值对做的不仅仅是直接把它输出，
but we have the beginnings now of a dynamic application.
但我们现在已经有了构建动态应用程序的雏形。
Any questions on any of this code or this framework thus far?
目前为止，对代码或框架有任何疑问吗？
Any questions thus far.
目前为止有任何问题吗？
No, all right, well, let's see what happens
没有，好的，我们来看看会发生什么
if I don't cooperate like a human.
如果我不像个正常人一样配合。
Let me actually go ahead and get rid of that parameter, hit Enter again,
让我继续删除那个参数，再按 Enter，
and I actually now got an HTTP 400 error.
实际上，我现在收到了一个 HTTP 400 错误。
So this actually seems bad.
所以，这看起来不太妙。
And it's a little subtle, but if I zoom into the tab here, it indeed says 400.
这有点微妙，但如果我放大这个标签，它确实显示的是 400。
That's one of the HTTP status codes that you generally shouldn't
这是 HTTP 状态码中的一种，你通常不应该
see unless something goes wrong.
看到，除非出了什么问题。
200 meant OK.
200 表示成功。
404 meant file not found.
404 表示文件未找到。
400 means that something went wrong.
400 表示发生了错误。
I guess I didn't pass in a name as I was supposed to.
我想我没有按要求传递 name。
But that's only because I was sort of blindly expecting this placeholder
但那是因为我有点盲目地期待这个占位符
to exist.
存在。
So let me be a little smarter and code a little more defensively now as follows.
所以，让我更聪明一点，现在更防御性地编写代码，如下所示。
Let me say this.
让我这么说。
How about if there is a name parameter in the requests arguments,
如果请求参数中存在 name 参数，
then go ahead and create a variable called name,
就创建一个名为 name 的变量，
set it equal to request.args, quote, unquote, "name".
把它设置为 request.args，引号，引号，"name"。
So treat it as a dictionary with that key.
所以把它当作一个带那个键的字典。
Else, if there is no name in the URL, let's
否则，如果 URL 中没有 name，我们就
just default this variable to being something sensible like,
将这个变量的默认值设置为一些合理的，例如，
quote, unquote, "world".
引号，引号，"world"。
So, now, let's proactively, using some sort of "week one style"
所以，现在，让我们主动地，使用某种“第一周风格”
conditional code, albeit in Python now from week six,
条件代码，尽管现在是来自第六周的 Python，
let's just check is name in the URL, if so grab its value.
让我们检查一下 URL 中是否包含 name，如果有，就获取它的值。
Otherwise, default to world instead.
否则，就默认为 world。
So I'm still going to leave this code as is,
所以我仍然会保留这段代码，
passing in the placeholder for this template to get plugged in here.
将这个占位符传递给这个模板，以便在这里插入。
But, now, if I go back to the browser and I just reload without passing
但是，现在，如果我回到浏览器，然后不传递
in name=David or anything else, now we have a sensible default.
name=David 或任何其他内容，现在我们得到了一个合理的默认值。
And if I go back to my View source tab and reload, I'll see that I have hello,
如果我返回到“查看源代码”标签并重新加载，我将看到“hello”，
world in this case.
在这种情况下是“world”。
However, if I go back up to that URL and do /?name=David, now we have David.
但是，如果我回到那个 URL 并执行 /?name=David，现在我们得到的是“David”。
If I change the URL to be name=Carter, now we have Carter.
如果我将 URL 改为 name=Carter，现在我们得到的是“Carter”。
So, indeed, we do have the beginnings of something that's more dynamic.
因此，确实，我们已经开始构建一些更加动态的东西了。
Of course, this is a little tedious to have
当然，这样做有点繁琐，因为
to write out this if and this else.
要写出这个 if 和 else。
There's ways to condense this code to be a little tighter and a little faster
有一些方法可以压缩这段代码，让它更紧凑，运行速度更快
to actually implement.
来实现。
And, in fact, let me go ahead and propose that.
实际上，让我来提议一下。
We just do this.
我们只要这样做。
Instead of treating args as a dictionary as
我们不要将 args 当作字典对待，因为
we did with square brackets-- which can cause problems
我们以前是用方括号处理的，这可能会导致问题
if that key does not exist.
如果该键不存在。
In fact, let me go back to that version.
实际上，让我回到那个版本。
Let me undo, undo, undo, whereby I'm just blindly
让我撤销，撤销，撤销，我正在盲目地
going into request.args to get name.
进入 request.args 获取 name。
In fact, instead of just blindly indexing into this dictionary
实际上，与其盲目地索引这个字典
called args, which turns out we can do this instead.
名为 args，我们可以用这种方式来代替。
Let me go ahead and say request.args.get,
让我说 request.args.get，
which is a function that comes with a dictionary,
这是一个字典自带的函数，
and I can specify the name of the key that I want to get.
我可以指定想要获取的键的名称。
And, by default, if there is no key called name in a dictionary,
默认情况下，如果字典中没有名为 name 的键，
you're going to get back a default value of none,
你将得到一个默认值 none，
which is kind of like Python's equivalent of null,
这有点类似于 Python 中 null 的等价物，
but it's none, capital N, in Python.
但在 Python 中它是 none，大写的 N。
But if you want to give it a different default,
但是，如果你想给它一个不同的默认值，
it's handy to know that this get function,
你需要知道这个 get 函数，
which you can use with dictionaries in general
它可以用于一般的字典，
can take a second argument, which will be the default
它可以接收第二个参数，这将是
value that you do get back if, in fact, there is no such key called name.
如果你实际上没有名为 name 的键，则会返回的默认值。
So what this means is I can actually now keep all of the code the same,
所以这意味着我现在可以保留所有代码不变，
but it's a little tighter.
但它更加紧凑。
There's no if or else.
没有 if 或 else。
I can go back to my other browser window, click reload,
我可以回到我的另一个浏览器窗口，点击重新加载，
and it still works for Carter.
它仍然适用于 Carter。
But if I get rid of that, I can now have hello,
但如果我去掉它，现在我可以有 hello，
world still working just as before.
world 仍然像以前一样工作。
And just to add one more potential point of confusion to the mix,
为了在混合中添加一个潜在的混淆点，
it's a little dopey to say placeholder literally in your template,
在你的模板中说占位符有点愚蠢，
especially if you're going to be using multiple pairs of curly braces for one
特别是如果你要在一个变量中使用多对花括号
variable or another or another.
或另一个，或另一个。
So better style would be to actually call
所以更好的风格是实际调用
the variable what makes sense for what it is you're plugging in.
变量的名称应该与你插入的值相对应。
So hello, name, with the name in curly braces.
所以 hello，name，花括号中是 name。
This is-- I show this, though, because it gets a little confusing
这个——我展示了这一点，因为这有点令人困惑
if your variable's called name, and that's still
如果你的变量叫做 name，那仍然
going to be the value you pass in.
将是你要传入的值。
You're going to very often see in the world of Flask
在 Flask 的世界里，你经常会看到
this convention, where you literally write something equals something where
这种约定，你写的是 something 等于 something，其中
the names there are exactly the same.
那里的名称完全相同。
And the only thing to keep in mind here is that the name--
这里需要注意的是，name——
this is the name of this parameter.
这是这个参数的名称。
This is the value of this parameter.
这是这个参数的值。
The fact that everything seems to be called name in this program
这个程序中的所有内容看起来都叫 name
is because these technical terms are colliding with the English word
是因为这些技术术语与我们熟悉的英语单词冲突了
that you and I know as name for my name, Carter's name, and so forth.
我们用它来表示我的名字、Carter 的名字等等。
But get past that only because it will be very common to literally see
但要克服这一点，因为你会经常看到
something equals something, where just for visual convenience
something 等于 something，仅仅是为了视觉上的方便
the variable's name is exactly the value that you want to pass in.
变量的名称恰好是你想要传入的值。
So that too here is conventional.
所以这里也是一种约定。
All right, a little cryptic.
好吧，有点神秘。
But common boilerplate that you'll start to see again and again.
但这是常见的模板代码，你会一遍又一遍地看到。
Any questions now about this?
现在还有关于这方面的疑问吗？
No?
没有？
OK, so let's make things a little more interesting and representative
好的，让我们让事情变得更有意思，更具代表性
of a real-world app.
像一个现实世界的应用程序。
Let me propose that, now, we go about implementing
我建议，现在，我们开始实现
maybe a second template altogether.
一个全新的第二个模板。
In fact, let me go ahead and do this.
实际上，让我来做一下。
It'd be nice if the human doesn't need to be technologically savvy enough
如果用户不需要精通技术，那会很棒
to say that, oh, if you want to be greeted by this website,
他们就能说，“哦，如果你想被这个网站问候，
you have to literally change the URL yourself, type in name equals--
你必须亲自修改 URL，输入 name 等于——
no one does that.
没有人会这样做。
That's just not how the web works in terms of user interface,
这并不是网页在用户界面方面的运作方式，
but that is how browsers and servers do work.
但浏览器和服务器确实是这么运作的。
But, of course, on the web, we almost always use forms.
当然，在网页上，我们几乎总是使用表单。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我来做一下。
Let me go into index.html, and let me get rid of just this hello, body.
让我进入 index.html，让我去掉这个 hello，body。
And, instead, let me actually create an HTML form.
然后，让我实际创建一个 HTML 表单。
This form is going to use the get method if only so that we can
这个表单将使用 get 方法，这样我们就可以
see what's going on inside of the URL.
看到 URL 中发生了什么。
This form is going to have an input where I'm going to turn autocomplete
这个表单将有一个输入，我将关闭自动完成功能
off, just like last week.
就像上周一样。
I'm going to do auto focus just to move the cursor there nicely by default.
我将使用自动聚焦功能，这样默认情况下光标就会很好地移动到那里。
Somewhat confusingly, I'm going to give this input a name of name
有点令人困惑的是，我要给这个输入一个名为 name 的名称
because I want Carter's name, my name, or someone else's human name.
因为我想要 Carter 的名字、我的名字，或其他人的名字。
But I'm going to give it placeholder text of,
但我将给它一个占位符文本，
quote, unquote, "Name", capitalized, just
引号，引号，“Name”，首字母大写，仅仅
to be grammatically clear as to what we're prompting the user for.
是为了在语法上清楚地表明我们正在提示用户输入什么。
And the type of this field is going to be text.
这个字段的类型将是文本。
Although, that's the implied default if I don't give it a type.
虽然，如果我不指定类型，那就是隐含的默认值。
I'm going to lastly have a button in this form, the type of which
最后，我将在表单中添加一个按钮，按钮的类型
is submit so that the browser knows to submit this form.
是提交，这样浏览器就知道要提交这个表单了。
And the label I'm going to put on this button is Greet.
我要在按钮上添加的标签是“问候”。
So I'm going to type in my name, click Greet.
所以我会输入我的名字，然后点击“问候”。
And I want to see hello, David or the like.
然后我想看到“你好，大卫”或类似的文字。
But I need to specify the action for this form.
但是，我需要指定这个表单的操作。
And recall that, when we implemented "Google", quote, unquote,
还记得，当我们实现“谷歌”的时候，
we did a little something like this.
我们做了一些类似的事情。
Https://www.google.com/search, well, we're
https://www.google.com/search，好吧，我们
not going to punt to Google today.
今天不会转到谷歌。
We are implementing our own applications.
我们正在实现我们自己的应用程序。
So if this were a search application, I could literally have an action
所以如果这是一个搜索应用程序，我可以直接有一个操作
of /search, but let's do something a little more semantically sensible.
为/search，但让我们做一些语义上更合理的事情。
Let's create our brand new route called /greet.
让我们创建一个名为/greet的新路由。
This is not the name of a folder.
这不是文件夹的名字。
It's not the name of a file.
这不是文件的名字。
It's more generically a path or a route that is now up to me to implement.
它更普遍地是一个路径或路由，现在由我来实现。
If I go back, though, to this application and reload this page,
不过，如果我回到这个应用程序并重新加载这个页面，
notice that I have the beginnings of a more user-friendly form
请注意，我有一个更友好的表单的雏形，
that's asking me for this name.
它正在询问我的名字。
However, if I do type in David and click Greet--
但是，如果我输入“大卫”并点击“问候”——
I'll zoom in just a moment--
我马上放大一下——
notice that the URL does change to /greet?name=David just like google.com
请注意，URL确实更改为/greet?name=David，就像google.com一样
works.
工作。
But, of course, we're getting a 404 not found because I
但是，当然，我们得到的是404错误，因为我
haven't implemented this route yet.
还没有实现这个路由。
So let me zoom out.
所以让我缩小。
Let me go back to VS Code.
让我回到VS Code。
Let me open app.py and make a little bit of a change there.
让我打开app.py，在那里做一些修改。
Let me make a little bit of a change and say this in app.py.
让我做一些修改，在app.py中这么说。
In app.py, instead of just getting the user's name and this default,
在app.py中，与其只是获取用户的姓名和这个默认值，
let's simplify the index route and just have it sole purpose in life
让我们简化索引路由，让它在生命中的唯一目的
be to render index.html, the thing that contains the form.
是渲染index.html，它包含表单。
I'm going to now, though, create a second route, so app.route, quote,
不过，我现在要创建一个第二个路由，所以app.route，引号，
unquote, "/greet".
引号，“/greet”。
And I could call this route anything I want.
我可以随意命名这个路由。
But greet seems sensible.
但是“问候”似乎很合理。
I'm going to call the function below it anything I want.
我将把下面的函数命名为我想要的任何名称。
But, just to keep myself sane, I'm going to call it the same thing as the route
但是，为了保持理智，我会把它命名为与路由相同的名称
even though that's not strictly required.
尽管这不是严格要求的。
And then, in this route, I'm going to go ahead and do this.
然后，在这个路由中，我将继续执行此操作。
I'm going to create a variable called name, set it equal to request.args.get,
我将创建一个名为name的变量，将其设置为request.args.get，
quote, unquote, "name", then, quote, unquote, "world", so
引号，“name”，然后，引号，“world”，所以
the exact same line as before.
与之前完全相同的代码行。
And then I'm going to return render_template, which
然后我将返回render_template，它
is the function that comes with Flask.
是Flask提供的函数。
I'm going to specify this time, though, render a template called greet.html--
不过，这次我将指定渲染一个名为greet.html的模板——
which doesn't exist yet, but that's not going to be a hard problem to solve--
它还没有创建，但这不会是一个难以解决的问题——
and pass in that variable.
并传入那个变量。
So the last thing I need to do is this.
所以我要做的最后一件事是这个。
And I'm going to cheat and copy and, in a moment,
我将作弊并复制，稍后，
paste the contents of index.html into a new file called greet.html as follows.
将index.html的内容粘贴到一个名为greet.html的新文件中，如下所示。
Let me open up VS Code here in my other terminal.
让我在另一个终端中打开VS Code。
Let me go ahead and write code templates/greet.html.
让我继续编写代码templates/greet.html。
Notice that I'm making sure to put the new file in the templates folder.
请注意，我确保将新文件放在templates文件夹中。
Or I could cd into it and then run the code command.
或者我可以进入它，然后运行代码命令。
That's going to give me a new file.
这将给我一个新文件。
I'm going to hide my terminal, paste that code,
我要隐藏我的终端，粘贴那段代码，
and I'm going to get rid of the form.
然后我会删除表单。
And, frankly, I should've just copied and pasted this earlier
坦率地说，我应该早点复制粘贴这个
because the only thing I'm going to put in greet.html is hello
因为我要放在greet.html中的唯一内容是“你好”
and then, in curly braces, my placeholder, which
然后，在大括号中，我的占位符，它
we started to call name a moment ago.
我们刚才开始称之为“name”。
So, to recap if I go into my terminal again, if I type ls,
所以，回顾一下，如果我再次进入我的终端，如果我输入ls，
I've still got app.py.
我仍然有app.py。
I've still got templates.
我仍然有templates。
But if I look inside of templates now, I've got two templates-- index.html
但是，如果我现在查看templates内部，我有两个模板——index.html
and greet.html. index.html is the thing you see when you visit my website.
和greet.html。index.html是你在访问我的网站时看到的内容。
greet.html is the thing you see when you submit that form, it would seem.
greet.html是你提交表单后看到的内容，似乎是。
So, indeed, if I go back to my browser and hit back--
所以，实际上，如果我回到浏览器并点击后退——
so I get back to that form.
我回到了那个表单。
For good measure, I'm going to reload because I
为了保险起见，我要重新加载，因为我
want to make sure I have the latest version of everything.
想要确保我有所有内容的最新版本。
I'm going to now try typing my name David.
我现在要尝试输入我的名字大卫。
I'll zoom in.
我会放大。
You'll see that the URL will again change to /greet with the question mark
你会看到URL再次更改为/greet，后面带一个问号
and my name.
和我的名字。
But, hopefully, we now indeed don't see a 404
但是，希望我们现在确实没有看到404错误
because the new route actually exists.
因为新路由确实存在。
And if I zoom out, right-click or Control-click
如果我缩小，右键单击或Ctrl+单击
and go to View page source, you still see
然后选择“查看页面源代码”，你仍然可以看到
what appears to be a HTML file just for me even though it was dynamically
似乎是一个专门为我准备的HTML文件，即使它是动态
generated instead.
生成的。
All right, if you're on board that this seems to be a correct application
好吧，如果你同意这似乎是一个正确的应用程序
insofar as it does what I wanted it to do,
因为它确实做了我想做的事情，
let's critique the design as we've been in the habit of doing.
让我们像往常一样批评一下设计。
I've now got three files, app.py, greet.html, and index.html.
我现在有三个文件，app.py、greet.html和index.html。
What might you not like about the design of this web application
即使你以前从未做过这些事情，你可能不喜欢这个网页应用程序的设计的哪些方面？
even if you've never done this stuff before?
即使你以前从未做过这些事情？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, greet and index.html have the same contents,
大卫·马兰：是的，greet和index.html的内容相同，
except for that one or few lines in the middle of the body.
除了主体中间的几行代码。
I mean, I literally copied and pasted, which, generally,
我的意思是，我确实是复制粘贴的，一般来说，
even though I do it sometimes in class to save time,
即使我偶尔在课堂上这样做来节省时间，
if I end up with the same code in my files,
如果我的文件中最终出现相同的代码，
that's probably cutting some corner and not the best design.
那可能是在走捷径，不是最好的设计。
Why?
为什么？
Well, what if I want to go in and change the title of this application
好吧，如果我想进去修改这个应用程序的标题
from hello to something else.
从 hello 改成别的呢？
It's not a huge deal.
没什么大不了的。
But I have to change it in two places.
但我得在两个地方修改。
What if I've got some pretty CSS that I've added?
如果我添加了一些漂亮的 CSS 呢？
And so I've got some CSS up here in one file.
然后我在一个文件中放了一些 CSS。
I need to copy it into another file, change it both places.
我需要把它复制到另一个文件中，在两个地方都修改。
Generally, having duplication of anything is bad design.
一般来说，任何东西的重复都是不好的设计。
So it turns out, there is a way to solve this.
事实证明，有一种方法可以解决这个问题。
And this is one of the features that you really
这是你真正能从 web 框架中获得的功能之一，无论是 Flask 还是其他任何框架。
start to get from a web framework, be it Flask or anything else.
你都能得到这些问题的解决方案。
You get solutions to these problems.
所以我接下来要做的就是
So what I'm going to do now is this.
我要为这个应用程序创建一个第三个也是最后一个文件
I'm going to create a third and final file for this application
首先复制我已有的内容。
by starting by copying what I have already.
让我回到我的终端窗口。
Let me go back to my terminal window here.
让我在模板文件夹中创建一个名为 layout.html 的第三个模板。
And let me create a third template in the templates folder called
它不必叫这个名字，但这是惯例。
layout.html.
所以我在这里总是这样做。
It doesn't have to be called that, but that's the convention.
当我创建这个文件并隐藏我的终端时，
So I'll always do that here.
我将复制粘贴所有内容。
And, when I create this file and hide my terminal,
但我将进入这个名为 layout.html 的文件的主体内部，
I'm going to go ahead and copy-paste all of that content.
除了其他方面之外，它在我的所有文件中都是相同的。
But I'm going to go inside of the body of this file, called layout.html,
我将使用稍微奇怪的语法。
which is otherwise identical across all of my files.
这更像是其他一些人类在几年前想出来的 Jinja 语法。
And what I'm going to do is use slightly weird syntax.
我要这样做。
This is more of that Jinja syntax that some other humans came up
单个大括号和一个百分号。
with years ago.
我要指定单词 block 以及我要为此块指定的任何名称。
And I'm going to do this.
按照惯例，我会保持简单
Single curly brace and a percent sign.
并只使用与我所处标签名称完全相同的内容，即 block body。
I'm going to specify the word block and then any name I want for this block.
然后，在右大括号之前，我会放一个百分号。
And, by convention, I'm going to keep it simple
我不需要这个内部的东西。
and just use the exact same thing as the name of the tag
所以乍一看，这也会很奇怪。
that I'm inside, so block body.
但这是一个惯例。
And then I'm going to put a percent sign just before the close curly brace.
我将使用另一个带有百分号的大括号
I don't need anything inside of this.
然后直接写 endblock，没有空格。
So this too's going to look weird at first glance.
我要打开和关闭一个不是 HTML 标签的东西。
But it's a convention.
如果你愿意，它是一个 Jinja 标签。
I'm going to do another curly brace with the percent sign
所以，你再次看到了世界上一些理性的人
and then literally the word endblock, no space.
在语法上存在分歧，
And I'm going to open and close what isn't an HTML tag.
或者至少使用在精神上相似的语法，
It's a Jinja tag, if you will.
但它与 HTML 已经使用的语法，即尖括号，并不冲突。
So, again, you see yet more evidence of reasonable humans
简而言之，这是一种指定
in the world kind of disagreeing on syntax
你想要一个占位符的方式，不仅仅是单个变量的值，
or at least using syntax that's similar in spirit
而是一整块代码。
but doesn't clash with the syntax, the angled brackets that HTML already uses.
它可能只是一句话。
Long story short, this is a way of specifying
它可能是一个完整的 web 表单元素或更多。
that you want a placeholder, not just for a single variable's value
现在这是一个代码块的占位符。
but for a whole block of code.
而我使用这个模板的方式——
Maybe it's simply a sentence.
这就是模板现在变得更加直观的地方
Maybe it's a whole-- a web form element or more.
在模板的作用意义上。
This is a placeholder now for a block of code.
我将这样做。
And the way I can do this-- or the way I can use this template--
我将进入我的另外两个文件，比如 greet.html。
and this is where template now is getting all the more literal
在这个文件中，与 index.html 相比，唯一不同的行是哪一行？
in the sense of what templates do.
第 9 行是唯一的一行。
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
所以我要做的是
I'm going to go into my two other files, like greet.html.
我将选中它并复制它。
The only line that's different in this file vis-a-vis index.html
然后我将删除此文件中所有其他内容，
is which line number?
因为它们只是多余的。
9 is the only line that is unique.
我需要的所有东西都在 layout.html 中。
So what I'm going to do is this.
在这个文件的顶部，我将使用另一个带有百分号的大括号，
I'm going to highlight that and copy it.
但我要使用一个特殊的关键字，
And then I'm going to delete everything else in this file
它与 Jinja 一起使用，称为 extends。
because it's just redundant.
我将在引号中指定我要扩展的模板名称，
Everything I need is in layout.html.
所以，这是一个在计算机科学中被称为继承的示例。
At the top of this file, I'm going to use another curly brace and a percent
我想从那个布局中获取所有内容，并从它继承
sign, but I'm going to use a special keyword that
所有行，但插入我自己的内容，
comes with Jinja called extends.
从某种意义上说，它是一种父子关系。
And I'm going to specify in quotes here the name of the template
在这个文件中，现在我将指定
that I want to extend, so to speak.
我想要的是这个 block body，就像之前一样。
So this is an example of what's in computer science known as inheritance.
然后，在下面，我将提前说 endblock，
I want to take everything from that layout and inherit from it
以提前完成我的想法。
all of its lines but plug in some of my own,
然后，在这个 block body 中，我将简单地粘贴我从原始版本中偷来的那行代码。
sort of from a parent-child relationship.
我承认这很丑陋。
Inside of this file, now, I'm going to specify
我添加了三行看起来很神秘的代码，所有这些代码
that the custom body that I want is this block body just like before.
都与 Jinja 模板相关，再次强调，这是人类发明的语法，
And then, down here, I'm going to preemptively say endblock just
它赋予了你编写模板的能力，
to finish my thought in advance.
或者说蓝图。
And then, inside of this block body, I'm going to simply paste that line of code
但重点是，这行代码，现在是第 5 行，
that I Stole from the original version.
将被插入到名为 layout.html 的模板中，
So I'll concede that this is pretty ugly.
无论 body 块在哪里。
I've added three cryptic-looking lines, all of which
最后，我要做的是
relate to Jinja templating, again, syntax
index.html 中唯一不同的行是这些，第 9、10、11、12 行。
that humans invented to give you the ability to write templates,
所以我要选中它们，并删除所有其他内容。
or blueprints.
然后我要做完全相同的事情，在顶部加上 extends layout.html
of this file, then, below that, block body.
这个文件的下面，然后在下面，block body。
Inside of the block body, I'm going to then say endblock at the end.
在block body的内部，我将在最后说endblock。
And, in the middle of that, I'm going to paste those lines of code.
然后，在中间，我将粘贴那些代码行。
Just stylistically, I'm going to indent them just so I'm super clear visually
仅从风格上来说，我将缩进它们，这样我从视觉上就能超级清楚
on what is inside of what.
什么在什么的里面。
But that's it.
就这样。
So ugly?
所以丑？
Yes, but, as soon as your web pages get longer and longer,
是的，但是，一旦你的网页变得越来越长，
this ends up being a drop in the bucket.
这最终将成为九牛一毛。
It's three ugly-looking lines relative to a lot of HTML
相对于你可能要插入和自定义到你的应用程序中的许多HTML来说，它只有三行难看的代码
that you might be plugging in and customizing for your application.
。
So now index.html looks like this.
所以现在index.html看起来像这样。
greet.html looks like this.
greet.html看起来像这样。
And the only way they differ is the actual contents of that block of code.
它们唯一不同之处在于那段代码块的实际内容。
layout.html is the main blueprint that's going to govern
layout.html是将要支配整个网站外观的主要蓝图
what the whole website looks like.
。
I can change the title in one place.
我可以在一个地方更改标题。
I can add some pretty CSS in one place and so forth.
我可以在一个地方添加一些漂亮的CSS等等。
It's going to apply to each of those files.
它将应用于每个文件。
And, now, somewhat underwhelmingly perhaps,
现在，也许有点令人失望，
if I go back to this application and I click reload,
如果我回到这个应用程序并点击重新加载，
nothing is different because it still just works.
没有什么不同，因为它仍然有效。
But I've made arguably a better design because now,
但我认为我做了一个更好的设计，因为现在，
when I change things to Carter here or I get rid of it altogether
当我在这里将内容更改为Carter或完全删除它时
and just visit the default--
并只访问默认--
rather, if I just visit slash there, I'll get the form.
更确切地说，如果我只是访问那里的斜杠，我将获得表单。
I've at least handled the situation where--
我至少处理了这种情况--
I've eliminated the situation where I've just copied and pasted
我消除了只是复制粘贴
the same boilerplate code.
相同的样板代码的情况。
So odds are someone like Google is doing something like this.
所以，像谷歌这样的公司很有可能正在做类似的事情。
It's probably fancier certainly than this example.
它可能比这个例子更花哨。
But any time you search for something on Google, generally, the top of the page
但无论何时你在谷歌上搜索任何东西，一般来说，页面的顶部
looks the same.
看起来都一样。
Maybe the bottom of the page looks the same.
也许页面的底部看起来也一样。
There's maybe some ads always at the top.
也许总是有一些广告在顶部。
And then there's 10 search results.
然后有10个搜索结果。
So, probably, what they've done is they have some template that looks roughly
所以，他们可能做的是，他们有一些模板，看起来大致
like this with all of the boilerplate stuff
像这样，包含所有他们希望每个人在每个搜索结果页面上都能看到的样板内容
that they want every human to see on every page of search results.
。
And then they're just somehow customizing the block--
然后他们只是以某种方式自定义了代码块--
a block of code somewhere there in the middle.
那里中间的代码块。
All right, questions on any of this actual templating technique?
好了，关于这种模板技术，有什么问题吗？
Anything at all?
任何问题吗？
All right, how about another question about design?
好的，关于设计，再问一个问题怎么样？
If I go back to this URL here and I search for something like David,
如果我回到这里这个URL，然后我搜索像David这样的东西，
it's not that big a deal that it ends up in the URL.
它最终出现在URL中，这并不算什么大不了的事。
And, in fact, what's nice about HTTP parameters ending up in the URL
事实上，HTTP参数最终出现在URL中，这样做的好处是
is that URLs are therefore stateful.
URL因此具有状态。
If you copy this URL and paste it into an email,
如果你复制这个URL并将其粘贴到电子邮件中，
assuming the web server is still up and running at that URL, it will just work.
假设web服务器仍然在那个URL上运行，它将正常工作。
And the human to whom you send that link,
而你发送链接给的人，
they will see David or Carter or whatever name's
他们将看到David或Carter，或者实际出现在那个表单中的任何名字。
actually in that form, which may be as useful behavior.
这可能是有用的行为。
Not so much for this application, but imagine now
这对这个应用程序来说并不重要，但现在想象一下
that you want to send someone a link of Google search results.
你想给某人发送一个谷歌搜索结果的链接。
It's a good thing that Google puts q=cats or dogs or birds or whatever
谷歌把q=cats或dogs或birds，或者任何东西
in the URL because then the URL itself is stateful.
放在URL中是一件好事，因为这样URL本身就具有状态。
What you see is what the recipient will see
你看到的就是接收者看到的内容
because all of the inputs of the server that's requisite is in that URL.
因为服务器的所有必需输入都在那个URL中。
But suppose that this form field, if I go back,
但假设这个表单字段，如果我返回，
wasn't asking for my name but my credit card number or my password up here.
它不是要求我的名字，而是要求我的信用卡号或我的密码。
That should start to rub you the wrong way because it
这应该让你开始感到不舒服，因为它
feels like no good will come from exposing private information in the URL
感觉从在URL中公开私人信息中不会有什么好处
because if you have a nosy sibling look over your shoulder.
因为如果你有一个爱窥探的兄弟姐妹从你肩膀上看。
There it is in your search history.
它就在你的搜索历史中。
A roommate goes through your autocomplete and finds the data there.
室友浏览你的自动完成并找到了数据。
Or if you do, for whatever reason, copy-paste it,
或者如果你出于任何原因复制粘贴它，
you're accidentally including private information in these URLs.
你无意中将私人信息包含在这些URL中。
So I said last week that there is an alternative to sending things
所以上周我说过，有一种在URL中发送内容的替代方法，那就是使用
in the URL and that alternative is to use something
不是get而是HTTP中的一个动词
that's not called get but a verb in the world of HTTP
叫做post。
that's called post instead.
它实际上是一个相对简单的改变。
And it's actually a relatively simple change.
如果我进入index.html，我可以简单地将方法从get改为post。
If I go into index.html, I can simply change the method from get to post.
get是默认值，post是另一种选择。
Get is the default. Post is an alternative.
尽管在某些情况下你会看到大写，但在HTML中，
Even though, in some contexts, you'll see capitals, in HTML,
它应该是小写，这是另一个左手不知道右手在做什么的例子。
it should be lowercase, another example of left hand not talking to right.
但在这种情况下，如果我现在转到我的浏览器中的另一个标签，
But, in this case, if I go now to my other tab with the browser,
重新加载页面，因为我想要获取表单的最新版本，
reload the page because I want to get the latest version of the form,
如果我现在输入David--
if I now type David--
并且我会放大--在按下回车键之前，如果你现在观察URL，
and I'll zoom in-- before hitting Enter, if you watch the URL now,
你应该不会看到?name=David在那里，
you should not see that ?name=David is up there,
你的信用卡或你的密码也不应该在那里。
nor would be your credit card or your password.
不幸的是，我们看到了另一个我们以前没有见过的HTTP状态
Unfortunately, we're seeing another HTTP status
代码，405，方法不允许。
code we haven't seen yet, 405, Method Not Allowed.
嗯，为什么呢？
Well, why is that?
那是因为现在我完全控制了web服务器，
That's because now that I fully control the web server,
我需要告诉web服务器我确实想要支持不仅是get
I need to tell the web server that I do want to support not just get
这个默认值，还有post。
which is the default but post as well.
用户正在使用的方法不受支持。
The method the user is using is not supported.
所以这是一个简单的修复，尽管它看起来
So this is an easy fix even though it's going
一开始会有点神秘。
to look a little cryptic at first.
如果你想要你的问候方法不仅支持get，还支持post，
If you want your greet method to support not just get but post,
那么你需要修改你的web服务器。
you can specify another argument to this route function.
你可以为这个路由函数指定另一个参数。
So the default is literally this, methods= and then in square brackets,
所以默认值就是这样，methods=，然后在方括号中，
quote, unquote, "GET".
引号、引号，“GET”。
So what is this?
所以这是什么？
Methods is apparently a named argument being passed into the route function.
Methods 显然是一个传递到路由函数的命名参数。
I claim its default value is this.
我认为它的默认值就是这个。
What do the square brackets indicate in Python?
在 Python 中，方括号表示什么？
Not a dictionary.
不是字典。
Square brackets.
方括号。
A list, so it's a list of strings or strs in this case.
一个列表，所以它是一个字符串列表或在这种情况下是 str。
This is the implicit default.
这是隐式的默认值。
So you don't have to type this.
所以你不需要输入这个。
It's just what works out of the box automatically.
它只是开箱即用，自动工作。
But if you want to change this from get to post,
但是如果你想从 get 更改为 post，
you have to include methods equals a list of the methods
你必须包含 methods 等于一个包含方法的列表，
that you do want to support.
你想要支持的那些。
For another time, there's other HTTP methods.
其他时间，还有其他 HTTP 方法。
There's delete.
有 delete。
There's put.
有 put。
Those are the two biggies that you might use as well.
这两个是你可能也会用到的重要方法。
Those are generally not supported as easily in the world of browsers,
在浏览器世界中，这些通常不容易支持，
but get and post certainly are.
但 get 和 post 当然可以。
If you wanted to support both for whatever reason,
如果你想支持这两个，无论出于什么原因，
you can literally have a comma separated list of those methods instead.
你可以直接使用用逗号分隔的那些方法列表。
But we don't really need both for privacy's sake.
但出于隐私考虑，我们并不需要两者。
I claim I'm only going to use post now.
我认为我现在只使用 post。
So now if I go back to my other tab, go back
所以现在如果我回到我的另一个标签，回到
to the form, reload to make sure everything is as expected,
表单，重新加载以确保一切按预期进行，
and now type in David and zoom in, you won't see my name in the URL.
现在输入 David 并放大，你将看不到我的名字在 URL 中。
But you will-- or you won't see it-- oh, good, not intended.
但你将会看到——或者你不会看到——哦，很好，不是故意的。
But nor will you see it even in the body of the web page.
但你甚至在网页正文中也看不到它。
So it's super secure.
所以它是超级安全的。
Why?
为什么？
I screwed up, but why?
我搞砸了，但为什么？
Yes.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yes, so good intuition.
大卫·J·马兰：是的，很好的直觉。
Even if you knew that before, you might think through rationally,
即使你之前知道，你也可以理性地思考，
how might this be--
这可能是什么——
why might this be behaving this way?
为什么会出现这种情况？
Well, if I go into app.py, it seems that if world is the value of the name
好吧，如果我进入 app.py，看起来如果 world 是 name 的值
placeholder, well, it must be the case that there is no name
占位符，那么一定是没有 name
key in request.args in this case.
在这种情况下，request.args 中的键。
However, there's an alternative to request.args,
然而，有一个 request.args 的替代方案，
and it's called request.form.
它叫做 request.form。
This is another example of visible and hidden being opposites of one another,
这是 visible 和 hidden 彼此相反的另一个例子，
request.args and request.form, at least for me,
request.args 和 request.form，至少对我来说，
are not obvious mappings to GET and POST, respectively.
并不是 GET 和 POST 的明显映射。
But that's what the Flask folks did.
但这就是 Flask 的人做的事情。
And so the simple fix now, if I go back to VS Code,
所以现在简单的修复方法是，如果我回到 VS Code，
is to change request.args to request.form
是将 request.args 更改为 request.form
if you want to use post instead of get.
如果你想使用 post 而不是 get。
This is a weird misnomer because they're both coming from forms,
这是一个奇怪的误称，因为它们都来自表单，
whether you're using GET or POST.
无论你使用 GET 还是 POST。
But this is what some folks decided.
但这是有些人决定的。
So let me go back to my browser, go back to the original form, reload
所以让我回到我的浏览器，回到原始表单，重新加载
to make sure I get the fresh HTML, type in my name now, David,
以确保我获取了最新的 HTML，现在输入我的名字，David，
zoom in, and click Greet.
放大，然后点击 Greet。
And, this time, you won't see my name in the URL,
而且，这次你将看不到我的名字在 URL 中，
but you should see it in the body of the page.
但你应该在网页正文中看到它。
So we've achieved some form of privacy, if you will.
所以我们实现了一种形式的隐私，如果你愿意。
Better applied to things like credit card numbers, passwords, and the like.
更好地应用于信用卡号码、密码等。
Phew, other questions?
呼，其他问题？
On any of this thus far?
关于到目前为止的任何内容？
Anything yet?
还有什么吗？
No, all right, yes, in the middle.
没有，好的，是的，中间。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] post and get, the request [INAUDIBLE]??
观众：[听不清] post 和 get，请求 [听不清]？
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
大卫·J·马兰：好问题。
To repeat if you were supporting both GET and POST,
重复一下，如果你同时支持 GET 和 POST，
should we have a second line that's also checking request.args?
我们是否应该有一个第二行也检查 request.args？
Yes, if you were.
是的，如果你这样做的话。
I, though, decided, at the last minute, only to support POST not GET.
不过，我在最后一分钟决定只支持 POST 而不是 GET。
So I don't have to bother with that.
所以我不必为此担心。
But your question's a perfect segue to a final example of this Hello application
但你的问题是这个 Hello 应用程序的最后一个例子的完美过渡，
where you can actually consolidate different types of functionality
在这里，你可以实际合并不同类型的功能，
into individual routes.
到单个路由中。
Why?
为什么？
Well, at the moment, this application is super simple.
好吧，目前，这个应用程序超级简单。
It's literally got one form and then one resulting page.
它实际上只有一个表单，然后一个结果页面。
But it's implemented, therefore, with a pair of routes, a pair of functions.
但是它因此是用一对路由，一对函数实现的。
No big deal for small applications.
对于小型应用程序来说，没什么大不了的。
But if you imagine a more complicated application,
但如果你想象一个更复杂的应用程序，
be it Google or anything else that has many different web
无论是谷歌还是任何其他拥有许多不同网页的网站，
forms on different pages, it's a little annoying
表单，它有点烦人
if every form needs to separate routes if only because you now
如果每个表单都需要单独的路由，仅仅因为你现在
have to keep track of literally twice as many functions.
必须跟踪实际两倍多的函数。
Your colleagues, your teaching fellow needs
你的同事，你的助教需要
to know which one is related to which.
知道哪一个与哪一个相关。
So there's something to be said design-wise
所以从设计的角度来说，
about consolidating related functionality into one single route
将相关功能合并到一个单一路由中，
so that everything is together.
这样所有东西都放在一起。
Well, we can achieve that relatively simply as follows.
好吧，我们可以通过以下方式相对轻松地实现这一点。
So let me go ahead and completely eliminate this greet route and simply
所以让我继续完全删除这个 greet 路由，并简单地
have everything exist in the /route.
让所有内容都存在于 /route 中。
And I'm going to go ahead and highlight and cut these lines out of there
我将继续突出显示并剪切这些行
altogether.
全部。
But if I want my single /route to support multiple methods,
但是如果我想让我的单个 /route 支持多种方法，
I indeed need to use methods equals and then, in square brackets, GET and POST.
我确实需要使用 methods 等于，然后在方括号中，GET 和 POST。
Order doesn't matter.
顺序无关紧要。
But I'll keep them alphabetical in this case.
但我会在这种情况下保持字母顺序。
Inside of my index route, I need to in advance is the user visiting me
在我的 index 路由中，我需要提前知道用户是通过 GET 还是 POST 访问我的
via GET or POST?
GET 还是 POST？
Because if it's via GET, I want them to see the form.
因为如果它是通过 GET 访问，我想让他们看到表单。
If it's via POST, I want to process, the form, that is,
如果是通过 POST 访问，我想处理表单，也就是说，
do something with the user's input.
对用户输入做一些操作。
So it turns out it's relatively simple.
所以事实证明这相对简单。
If request.method equals equals "POST", then I can do the following.
如果 request.method 等于等于 "POST"，那么我可以执行以下操作。
So you can literally check the request object, which comes with Flask,
所以你可以直接检查 request 对象，它来自 Flask，
to figure out, was the word GET or the word POST in that virtual envelope?
来确定，那个虚拟信封中是 GET 还是 POST？
And, depending on the answer, you can do something like this.
根据答案，你可以做一些类似的事情。
I can paste those lines from earlier, whereby I get
我可以粘贴之前那些行，这样我就可以得到
the variable name from request.form.
request.form 中的变量名称。
And then I render the template greet.html, passing in that name.
然后我渲染 greet.html 模板，并将那个名称传递进去。
Otherwise, you know what?
否则，你知道吗？
I could just do else, return the template itself.
我只需要使用 else，返回模板本身。
So if the method is POST, go ahead and process the form just as we did before.
所以如果方法是 POST，继续处理表单，就像我们之前做的那样。
Else, go ahead and just render the index template which contains the form.
否则，继续渲染包含表单的 index 模板。
Strictly speaking, I don't even need the else.
严格来说，我甚至不需要 else。
I can get rid of that, just to tighten this up a little bit,
我可以去掉它，只是为了让代码更加简洁，
and unindent my last line.
并且缩进我的最后一行。
Why?
为什么？
Because recall that, from C, from Python, as soon as you return a value,
因为回想一下，从 C 到 Python，一旦你返回一个值，
nothing in that function is going to get executed thereafter.
该函数中没有任何内容会随后被执行。
So you might as well kind of tighten up the code so
所以你最好尽可能地让代码更加简洁，
that you don't bother adding undue indentation if not needed.
这样你就不用在不需要的情况下添加不必要的缩进。
So notice, now, if I go back to my browser, reload here,
所以注意，现在，如果我回到我的浏览器，在这里刷新，
it's not going to work yet.
它还不能工作。
But let's see if you can diagnose the issue.
但让我们看看你是否可以诊断出问题。
If I type in David here and click Greet, now I'm
如果我在此处输入 David 并点击 Greet，现在我
back to getting a 404 but for different reasons.
又回到了 404，但原因不同。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Good, I haven't changed-- not the method.
DAVID J. MALAN：很好，我没有更改——不是方法。
But I haven't changed the action in the form itself.
但我没有更改表单本身的动作。
So if I go back to VS Code here and I go into the web forms,
所以如果我回到 VS Code，进入 web 表单，
the HTML, POST is still fine.
HTML 中的 POST 仍然没问题。
But there is no /greet route anymore.
但不再有 /greet 路由了。
So I actually can just specify slash.
所以实际上我只需要指定斜线。
Or it turns out if you omit that altogether, the form will assume
或者事实证明，如果你完全省略它，表单会假设
that you want to submit it to the very route from which you
你想要提交到你的路由
came so that is fine as well.
来源，所以这也很好。
I'm going to go ahead now and go back to that other tab and go back.
我现在将返回到另一个标签并返回。
I'm going to reload the page.
我将重新加载页面。
And, just for good measure, this time, I'm
为了安全起见，这次我
going to Control-click or right-click View page source.
将使用 Control-click 或右键点击查看页面源代码。
And, here, yep, the action has indeed updated.
这里，是的，动作确实更新了。
So I think I fixed the bug.
所以我想我已经修复了 bug。
Now if I type in David and click greet, we're back in business with it working.
现在如果我输入 David 并点击 greet，我们又可以正常使用了。
So notice that this still allows me the convenience
所以注意，这仍然允许我方便地
of having two separate templates, one for the form which shows the--
拥有两个独立的模板，一个是用于表单的，它显示了——
which collects the user input and one for the actual greeting
用于收集用户输入的，另一个用于实际的 greeting
which displays the user input.
用于显示用户输入的。
So I'd argue that it still makes sense to keep those separate.
所以我会说，将它们分开仍然是有意义的。
But I can avoid bloating my app.py by having
但我可以避免让我的 app.py 文件膨胀，因为我
two methods for every single feature that I might want to implement.
为我想要实现的每个功能都创建了两个方法。
Now, there is still a bug in this implementation
现在，尽管它有点细微，但这个实现中仍然存在一个 bug。
even though it's a little bit subtle.
即使它有点细微。
So recall that, previously, we introduced this default value of world
所以回想一下，之前，我们引入了 world 的默认值
just in case the form doesn't actually contain the word world
以防表单实际上不包含 world 这个词
as might've happened if I didn't-- if I [INAUDIBLE] into the URL that I was
就像我之前没有——如果我 [听不清] 到我正在请求的 URL
requesting manually as I did before.
手动请求一样。
But it turns out that if you're using an actual form and not,
但事实证明，如果你使用的是一个实际的表单，而不是
of course, expecting the human to type anything into the URL bar, which
当然，希望用户在 URL 栏中输入任何内容，而
no human would do, it turns out that the browser is still
没有人会这样做，事实证明浏览器仍然
going to submit a name parameter even if its value is blank,
会提交一个 name 参数，即使它的值为空，
that is, empty, the so-called empty string.
也就是说，为空，所谓的空字符串。
And so even if it's the empty string, it's
所以即使它是空字符串，它
still going to be considered to be a value
仍然会被视为一个值
and, therefore, not worthy of having the default value of world plugged in.
因此，不值得插入 world 的默认值。
In other words, if I open up my terminal window here, rerun flask run,
换句话说，如果我在这里打开我的终端窗口，重新运行 flask run，
and go back over to my browser, and load this example, if I type in David,
然后回到我的浏览器，加载这个例子，如果我输入 David，
as before, I'm going to be greeted with hello, David.
和之前一样，我会收到 hello, David 的问候。
But if I try this again and don't provide an actual name but just click
但如果我再试一次，不提供实际的名称，只点击
Greet, it turns out the name parameter's still
Greet，事实证明 name 参数仍然
going to be submitted to the server, in which case request.form.get is not
会提交给服务器，在这种情况下，request.form.get 不会
going to rely on the default value but rather that empty string value.
依赖于默认值，而是依赖于那个空字符串值。
And so we see what appears to be a bit of an aesthetic bug hello, nothing.
所以我们看到的是一个看起来像是审美上的 bug，hello, nothing。
So how can we go about fixing this?
那么我们该如何修复它呢？
Well, perhaps the simplest way is to no longer rely on this default
也许最简单的方法是不再依赖于 app.py 中的这个默认值。
value here inside of app.py.
所以，事实上，让我删除那个默认值，
So, in fact, let me go ahead and delete that default value altogether
并将 name 作为变量传递到 greet.html，我们的模板中。
and pass name in as the variable it still is into greet.html, our template.
但在 greet.html 中，让我们添加一些逻辑
But, in greet.html, let's add a bit of logic
在那里，如果 name 不为空，我们就条件地显示它。
there whereby we conditionally display the name if and only if it's not empty.
换句话说，在我盲目地输出这些大括号中的 name 之前，
In other words, before I output blindly name inside of these curly braces,
让我借用 Python 的一些语法，在我的 Jinja 模板中实际使用一个条件语句。
let me borrow some syntax from Python and actually use, within my Jinja
打开大括号，然后是一个百分号，因为这次，
template, a conditional like this.
我需要逻辑，而不仅仅是变量的插值。
Open curly brace and then a percent sign because, this time,
我将说 if name。
I want logic, not just interpolation of a variable.
然后我将使用另一个百分号和一个单大括号。
And I'm going to say if name.
。
And then I'm going to do another percent sign and a single curly brace.
And then, after that, I'm going to still use my variable name name
然后，在那之后，我仍然会使用我的变量名 name
inside of two curly braces.
在两个花括号中。
But, after that, I'm going to do again a single curly brace, a single percent
但是，在那之后，我会再次使用一个单花括号，一个单百分号
sign, and then I'm going to say else followed by one more percent sign.
符号，然后我会说 else，后面再加一个百分号。
And then, after that, I'm going to go ahead and actually put my default value
然后，在那之后，我会继续并将我的默认值
world and then close this if conditional with a single curly brace,
world 然后用一个单花括号关闭这个 if 条件语句，
a single percent sign, and endif.
一个单百分号，以及 endif。
And then I'm going to go ahead and close that tag there.
然后我会继续关闭那里的标签。
So, in Jinja, it turns out that we can use it not only to plug in values.
所以，在 Jinja 中，事实证明，我们不仅可以用来插入值。
We can also do a bit of lightweight conditional logic using
我们还可以使用它来进行一些轻量级的条件逻辑，使用
an if and an else and an endif in this case, which
一个 if、一个 else 和一个 endif，在本例中，它
isn't quite like Python-- indeed the endif is a little bit different.
与 Python 不太一样——实际上 endif 有点不同。
But this is particular now to the Jinja template.
但这现在是 Jinja 模板所特有的。
And I've done it all on one line just because this
而我把它全部写在一行上，仅仅因为
is a fairly bit-sized conditional, either print out the name
是一个相当简单的条件语句，要么输出姓名
or print out world.
要么输出 world。
Otherwise, I could actually put these template tags on their own lines
否则，我实际上可以将这些模板标签放在它们自己的行上
in order to spread things out all the more.
以便更加分散内容。
We'll see now, before long, that there's actually
我们很快就会看到，实际上
some other control flow capabilities of Jinja including loops and more.
Jinja 还有一些其他的控制流功能，包括循环等等。
But, for now, this is a nice way to solve that one problem because now,
但现在，这是一个解决那个问题的好方法，因为现在，
when I go back into my application and I go back to the form and type
当我回到我的应用程序，回到表单并输入
in D-A-V-I-D, it's still going to work as expected, hello, David.
D-A-V-I-D，它仍然会按预期工作，你好，David。
But if I go back one final time, type nothing in thereby sending
但如果我最后一次回去，什么都不输入，从而发送
an empty value to the server and click Greet here to demonstrate as much,
一个空值到服务器，并点击这里问好来展示这一点，
now we do, in fact, see hello, world.
现在，我们确实看到了，你好，世界。
All right, any questions on this final example of just saying hello?
好的，关于这个最后简单问好的例子，还有什么问题吗？
From those basics come pretty much all of dynamic web applications today.
从这些基础知识中，几乎所有今天的动态网页应用程序都由此而来。
No?
没有？
All right, so if you'll indulge me, here's an actual web application
好的，如果你能容忍我，这儿有一个真正的网页应用程序
that I made back in the day.
我以前做过的。
So, when I was a sophomore, I think I was not very athletic,
所以，当我还是个大二学生的时候，我想我并不擅长运动，
so I didn't so much do freshman intramural sports as I did run them
所以我没有参加大一学生校内运动会，而是管理它们
with a roommate of mine.
和我的一位室友一起。
So we were sophomores in Mather House.
所以，我们是梅瑟楼的大二学生。
He was the athlete.
他是运动员。
I was the aspiring computer scientist.
我是有抱负的计算机科学家。
And so this was actually a screenshot of the very first web application
所以，这实际上是我做的第一个网页应用程序的截图
I ever made.
我曾经做过。
And this will sound old too.
而且这个听起来也很古老。
But, back in my day, freshman year, when we
但是，在我那个年代，大一的时候，当我们
registered for Frosh IMs, or Freshman Intramural Sports,
注册参加新生校内运动会，或者说新生校内运动会，
you would literally walk across Harvard yard
你真的会穿过哈佛庭院
to Wigglesworth, where a certain proctor or RA lived who was running Frosh IMs.
去维格尔斯沃斯，那里住着一位负责管理新生校内运动会的辅导员或助教。
And you would literally slide a sheet of paper
然后你真的会把一张纸
under the door with your name on it and your choice of sports
塞到门底下，上面写着你的名字，还有你选择的运动
that you want to register for.
你想注册的运动。
So that was the state of the art in 1995.
所以，这就是 1995 年的最新技术。
This was ripe for disruption as people would now say.
正如人们现在所说，这是颠覆的时机。
And, once I actually took CS50 in the fall of 1996, which did not
而且，当我 1996 年秋天真正开始学习 CS50 课程时，当时课程并没有
teach, funny enough, web programming at the time,
教，有趣的是，当时并没有教网页编程，
I think I spent that winter or spring figuring out
我想我花了那个冬天或春天来弄清楚
how to do stuff with web programming, not using C and not even using Python.
如何用网页编程做一些事情，不是用 C，甚至不用 Python。
At the time, I was using a language called Perl, which is still with us
当时，我使用的是一种叫做 Perl 的语言，它现在仍然存在
but not as popular as it was back in the day.
但它不像以前那样流行了。
But what you're seeing here is a hideous screenshot
但是，你在这里看到的只是一个可怕的截图
of what the user interface was.
用户界面是什么样子的。
This was me learning how to repeat background in images infinitely,
我当时正在学习如何无限地重复图像中的背景，
no matter how big the page was.
无论页面有多大。
Back in the day, there was no CSS, I think, even at the time.
在我那个年代，我认为当时甚至还没有 CSS。
So every one of these menu options was actually an image.
所以，这些菜单选项中的每一个实际上都是一张图片。
And even though-- this is a screenshot, so it's not animated.
即使——这是一个截图，所以它没有动画。
If you would hover over any of these words, what
如果你把鼠标悬停在这些词语的上面，你会发现，
I would do using JavaScript, which did exist in an early form,
我会使用 JavaScript 来做，它在早期确实存在，
was just change the image from a blue image to a red image,
只是将图片从蓝色图片改为红色图片，
creating the illusion of the trickery we did last week with text decoration,
营造出我们上周用文本装饰做的欺骗的错觉，
as you might recall in hover.
你可能还记得 hover 中的例子。
So the web's come a long way.
所以，网页已经走过了很长的路。
But this is still representative, amazingly, some 20 years later
但令人惊讶的是，在 20 年后的今天，这仍然代表着
of how web applications still work.
网页应用程序是如何工作的。
I used a different language.
我使用了一种不同的语言。
I used a different backend for my data or database.
我使用了一个不同的后端来存储我的数据或数据库。
But everything I did then we will now do effectively today
但是，我当时做的一切，我们现在都可以有效地做到今天
and beyond because the principles have not changed.
以及将来，因为原理没有改变。
It's all based ultimately on HTTP and all of the stuff
它最终都是基于 HTTP 和所有我们讨论过的事情
we discussed thus far this past week and now this.
我们在过去一周以及现在讨论过的所有事情。
So let's go ahead and make the beginnings of this website,
所以让我们开始构建这个网站，
though, perhaps without as many of the hideous images underneath it.
不过，也许不需要那么多难看的图片。
In my VS Code, I'm going to go ahead and close all of my prior tabs.
在我的 VS Code 中，我会继续关闭我之前的所有标签。
I'll open up my terminal, and I'll hit Control-c to exit out
我会打开我的终端，然后按 Control-c 来退出
of Flask just like you can hit Control-c to exit out of the HTTP server.
Flask，就像你可以按 Control-c 来退出 HTTP 服务器一样。
I'm going to go ahead and hit cd to go back to my main workspace.
我会继续按 cd 返回到我的主工作区。
And I'm going to create a new folder with mkdir called froshims
我会用 mkdir 创建一个名为 froshims 的新文件夹
so that all of my new application is inside of this folder.
这样我的所有新应用程序都会在这个文件夹中。
I'm going to cd into froshims.
我会进入 froshims 文件夹。
And let's go ahead and make a very simple application
让我们继续做一个非常简单的应用程序
that essentially pretends to let first years register for a sport.
它本质上是模拟让大一新生注册一项运动。
So I'm going to need to do a bit of typing up front.
所以，我需要先输入一些东西。
But I'll do the first one from scratch.
但我会从头开始做第一个。
And then we'll start just evolving that same example.
然后我们将开始逐步改进同一个例子。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续这样做。
Let me go ahead and--
让我继续...
actually, we'll do this.
实际上，我们会这样做。
We'll cut one corner.
我们将省去一个步骤。
I'm going to go ahead and copy, from my hello example, app.py into this folder.
我将从我的hello示例中复制app.py到这个文件夹中。
I'm going to go ahead and copy from my hello examples
我将从我的hello示例中复制
templates my layout into this folder.
模板布局到这个文件夹中。
I'm going to create a new folder called templates.
我将创建一个名为templates的新文件夹。
I'm going to move that copied layout into templates
我将把复制的布局移动到templates文件夹中
so that, at this point in the story, if I clear my screen and type ls,
这样，在故事的这个阶段，如果我清除屏幕并键入ls，
I've got the beginnings of a web application,
我已经有了web应用程序的雏形，
even though it's specific to just saying hello.
即使它仅仅用于说“你好”。
But I'm going to go ahead and into the templates folder
但我将进入templates文件夹
and go into layout.html.
并进入layout.html。
Let's just change this ever so slightly to say froshims as the title
我们只需稍作修改，将标题改为froshims
just so we know we're looking at the right application.
这样我们就知道我们在看正确的应用程序。
And, now, let me go ahead and create a new file called how
现在，让我创建一个名为how的新文件
about index.html inside of templates that,
名为index.html，位于templates文件夹中，
just as before, is going to extend that there template, so extends layout.html.
就像之前一样，它将扩展该模板，所以extends layout.html。
Inside of here, I'm going to say block body just as before.
在这里，我将像之前一样写block body。
Preemptively going to say endblock.
提前说endblock。
And then, inside of here, I'm going to make
然后，在里面，我将制作
the beginnings of a super simple web page for first-year intramural.
一个非常简单的网页，用于第一年的校内比赛。
So I'm going to use an h1 tag that's sort of big and bold that
所以我将使用一个h1标签，它比较大而且粗体，
just says register at the top of the page sort of like a title.
在页面的顶部写着“注册”，就像一个标题一样。
Below that, I'm going to have a form.
在下面，我将有一个表单。
The action of this form I'm going to say proactively is going to say
这个表单的动作我将提前说
to /register.
是/register。
So that's a to do.
所以这是一个待办事项。
We're going to have to go implement a register route.
我们需要去实现一个注册路由。
The method I'm going to use is post just for privacy's sake
我将使用post方法，仅仅是为了隐私
so that if roommates are sharing the same computer,
这样，如果室友共用同一台电脑，
they don't see, in the autocomplete, who's registered for what.
他们在自动完成中就不会看到谁注册了哪个项目。
Inside of that form, I'm going to have a single input first where
在表单中，我将首先添加一个输入框，其中
autocomplete is off.
自动完成已关闭。
Autofocus is on.
自动聚焦已开启。
The name of this field will be name because I want
这个字段的名称将是name，因为我想要
to ask the humans for their human name.
询问用户他们的名字。
The placeholder, just to be self-describing,
占位符，为了自我描述，
is going to be, quote, unquote, "Name", capital N grammatically.
将是，“Name”，语法的首字母大写。
And then, lastly, the type of this field, though it's the default,
最后，这个字段的类型，虽然是默认的，
is text.
是文本。
So, so far, this is actually pretty darn similar to the hello example
所以，到目前为止，这实际上与hello示例非常相似
soliciting someone's name.
用于请求某人的名字。
But now I want to maybe implement a dropdown
但现在我可能想实现一个下拉菜单
menu via which you can select a sport.
供用户选择项目。
And, back in the day, I think the first version of froshims,
在过去，我认为froshims的第一个版本，
students could only register for basketball, soccer,
学生只能注册篮球、足球，
and ultimate Frisbee.
和极限飞盘。
So those were three of the fall sports.
所以那些是秋季的三项运动。
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
It's a little weirdly named, but a dropdown menu in HTML
名字有点奇怪，但在HTML中，下拉菜单
is called a select menu because you select something from it.
被称为选择菜单，因为你从中选择一些东西。
The name of this input, which is really what it is, is going to be sport.
这个输入框的名称，它实际上就是输入框，将是sport。
Though, I could call the input anything I want.
不过，我可以随意命名这个输入框。
And, inside of this select element, I'm going to have a few options.
在这个选择元素中，我将添加一些选项。
I'm going to have one where the option is how about basketball?
我将添加一个选项，选项内容是篮球？
Another option, the value of which is soccer.
另一个选项，其值为足球。
And, lastly, a third option, the value of which is ultimate Frisbee.
最后，第三个选项，其值为极限飞盘。
So just those three sports.
所以只有这三项运动。
But suffice it to say we could add even more.
但可以肯定地说，我们可以添加更多。
And then, outside of this select menu, I'm
然后，在这个选择菜单之外，我
going to have a button just like the hello example, the type of which
将添加一个按钮，就像hello示例一样，类型为
is submit, just to be super explicit even though that's not
提交，为了超级明确，即使这不是
strictly necessary.
严格必需的。
But it's another attribute you'll see in the wild.
但这是你在实际应用中会看到的另一个属性。
And then the name on the value of this button will be register.
然后这个按钮的值的名称将是register。
So it's clear that you're not being greeted,
所以很明显你没有被问候，
but you're actually registering for sports.
而是正在注册运动项目。
Now, we're not quite good to go yet, but let me go into VS code's terminal
现在，我们还没有完全准备好，但让我进入VS code的终端
again.
再来一次。
Let me open up app.py and close my terminal again.
让我打开app.py并再次关闭终端。
And let's just whittle this down to something super simple.
让我们简化一下。
I don't want to get overwhelmed just yet.
我现在不想过度复杂化。
I don't want to support even POST.
我甚至不想支持POST。
So let's just whittle this down to the essence of this.
所以让我们简化到这个的本质。
So I can do a quick check mentally and make sure now,
这样我就可以在脑海里快速检查一下，并确保现在，
when I run flask, that I'm serving up that registration form.
当我运行flask时，我正在提供注册表单。
So, in my terminal, I'm going to run flask run in my froshims folder.
所以，在我的终端中，我将在我froshims文件夹中运行flask run。
So far, so good.
目前为止，一切顺利。
It's going to be by default the same URL unless I've rebuilt or created
默认情况下，它将是相同的URL，除非我重新构建或创建
a brand new codespace.
一个全新的代码空间。
So let me go back to my other tab and reload that URL.
所以让我回到我的另一个标签并重新加载那个URL。
And, OK, we've got the beginnings of a more interesting form now.
好了，我们现在有了更有趣的表单的雏形。
So it's got place for my name.
所以它有我的名字的输入框。
It's got a dropdown for the three sports.
它有三个运动项目的下拉菜单。
So let's see what happens, D-A-V-I-D. We'll say soccer.
让我们看看会发生什么，D-A-V-I-D。 我们选择足球。
And, when I click Register, just to be clear, what route will
然后，当我点击注册时，为了明确起见，我将进入哪个路由？
I find myself at per my URL?
我的URL是？
Slash.
斜杠。
What was it to be?
应该是什么？
If I go back into my index.
如果我回到我的index中。
/register.
/register。
But what error will I see presumably at this point in time,
但在这个时间点，我预计会看到什么错误？
given that app.py has only been implemented to this extent?
鉴于app.py只实现了到目前为止的程度？
So probably 404 because the route won't be found.
所以可能是 404 错误，因为找不到路由。
So if I click Register, I indeed end up at /register.
如果我点击注册，确实会跳转到 /register 页面。
But if I zoom in up top here, 404 not found.
但如果我在顶部放大，就会显示 404 错误。
All right, so it's the beginnings of an application.
好的，这是一个应用程序的雏形。
But I've not-- I've implemented the front end, so to speak,
但是我还没有实现所谓的“前端”，
the user interface but not the back end, the business logic that actually
也就是说，我实现了用户界面，但没有实现后端，以及处理用户输入的业务逻辑。
does something with the user input.
它实际上会对用户输入进行处理。
But a couple of enhancements here.
但是这里有一些改进。
But these are largely niceties in HTML.
但这些基本上是 HTML 中的一些小细节。
It's a little bad user experience that by default you're
默认情况下，这会导致用户体验不太好，因为你正在
registering for basketball.
注册参加篮球运动。
I mean, that's fine.
我的意思是，这没什么问题。
But, arguably, you're biasing people toward registering for basketball.
但可以这么说，你正在引导人们注册参加篮球运动。
Or they might not realize that they're registering for basketball because they
或者他们可能没有意识到他们正在注册参加篮球运动，因为他们
didn't explicitly choose a sport.
没有明确选择一项运动。
So having a random, an arbitrary default that
所以有一个随机的、任意的默认值，
just happens to be the first word alphabetically
恰好是字母顺序排列的第一个词，
is a little weak when it comes to design.
在设计方面，这有点弱。
So there's different ways to fix this.
所以有很多方法可以解决这个问题。
But one way is to do this.
但是一种方法是这样做。
Add a new option at the very top.
在最上面添加一个新的选项。
But go ahead and disable it so that the user can't themselves
然后禁用它，这样用户就不能自己
select it because you want them to select an actual sport.
选择它，因为你想让他们选择一项真正的运动。
By default, you can specify that it's indeed selected.
默认情况下，你可以指定它已经被选中。
And it has no value.
并且它没有值。
So not to judge any sport, but this particular option has no value.
所以不是针对任何运动，而是这个特定选项没有值。
But what the human sees is the word sport, for instance.
但是用户看到的是“运动”这个词，例如。
So this is kind of a hack.
所以这有点像一种技巧。
Ideally, the Select menu would just have a placeholder attribute
理想情况下，下拉菜单应该有一个占位符属性，
like the actual input boxes does.
就像实际的输入框一样。
But that does not exist.
但它不存在。
So if I reload now, it looks a little more user friendly.
所以如果我现在重新加载，它看起来更友好一些。
So it says sport.
上面显示着“运动”。
I can't select sport ever again.
我再也不能选择“运动”了。
But it is the default, but I can select one of these three sports
但它仍然是默认选项，但我可以选择这三种运动之一，
which just increases the probability that the human does
这仅仅增加了用户执行你预期操作的概率。
what you might expect.
这是你可能期望的结果。
Of course, there's something else I can add here.
当然，这里还可以添加其他东西。
Suppose I don't even give my name.
假设我甚至没有输入我的名字。
It still went through.
它仍然能够提交。
It didn't work.
它没有成功。
It's still a 405, but the--
它仍然是 405 错误，但...
404.
404 错误。
But the browser didn't stop me.
但是浏览器并没有阻止我。
So recall that we do have some other tricks.
所以请记住，我们还有一些其他技巧。
For instance, I can say that this dropdown, this select menu
例如，我可以说这个下拉菜单，这个选择菜单
is itself required-- or, sorry, not this one.
本身是必需的 - 或者，抱歉，不是这个。
The text box is itself required, for instance.
例如，文本框本身是必需的。
So now if I go back to the form and reload
所以现在如果我回到表单并重新加载，
and I just ignore the name question and click Register,
而我只忽略了姓名问题并点击注册，
the browser's going to yell at me.
浏览器就会提醒我。
Now, recall that this is not robust.
现在，请记住，这不是很稳健。
Client-side validation is not good.
客户端验证并不可靠。
Why?
为什么？
What'd we learn last week?
我们上周学到了什么？
Yeah, I mean, I can literally right-click or Control-click
是的，我的意思是，我可以直接右键点击或 Ctrl+点击
and open up Developer Tools.
打开开发者工具。
I can go into that form using the Developer Tools.
我可以使用开发者工具进入那个表单。
I can literally find the word required, delete it, and voila.
我可以直接找到“required”这个词，删除它，然后就成功了。
This form will now go through because the browser's
这个表单现在可以提交了，因为浏览器
going to do what I change.
会按照我修改的方式运行。
So it's useful for user experience, making just things a little prettier
所以它对用户体验很有用，可以使一些东西看起来更漂亮，
and faster to validate.
并且可以更快地进行验证。
But it's not going to be robust defense.
但这并不能提供可靠的防御。
All right, so let's go back now to VS Code into my actual route
好的，现在让我们回到 VS Code 中的实际路由，
and implement at least something here that resembles registration.
在这里实现一些类似于注册的东西。
So I'm going to go into app.py.
所以我要进入 app.py 文件。
And, in app.py, let's create this second route.
在 app.py 文件中，让我们创建第二条路由。
So, at app.route, quote, unquote, "/register"
所以，在 app.route，引号之间输入“/register”，
to match what is in my HTML.
与我的 HTML 中的路由匹配。
Let me define a function.
让我定义一个函数。
I can call it anything I want.
我可以随意命名它。
But, again, good convention to just call it the same thing as the route
但是，再次强调，一个好的习惯是将函数命名为与路由相同的名称，这样就不会出现不同步的情况。
name so you don't get out of sync.
这样就不会出现不同步的情况。
And then there's a couple of things I might want to do.
然后，我可能想做几件事。
When you register for this particular form,
当你在这个特定表单上注册时，
what are the two things that the server should probably check for?
服务器应该检查哪些内容？
What kind of logic should I have here?
我这里应该写什么逻辑？
Yeah.
对。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] at anything for [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：[听不清]任何东西 [听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so let's make sure that the name is present
DAVID J. MALAN: 好的，让我们确保姓名存在，
and the sport is present, ideally.
并且最好还存在运动项目。
So let's actually validate the user's input just like get int
所以让我们实际上验证用户输入，就像第一周的 get int 函数一样。
did back in week one.
就像第一周的 get int 函数一样。
Just like get string, get float, and all of those,
就像 get string 函数、get float 函数以及所有这些函数一样，
they made sure that you actually got input.
它们确保你确实获得了输入。
So there's a bunch of ways I can do this,
所以有很多方法可以做到这一点，
but I'm going to go ahead and take a relatively canonical approach.
但我将使用一种比较标准的方法。
If not request.form.get, quote, unquote, "name",
如果 request.form.get 函数获取到的 "name" 值不存在，
I'm going to go ahead and then return, how about let's just see,
我将继续执行并返回，让我们看看，
failure, quote, unquote, "failure" just as a quick and dirty solution.
返回 “failure” 作为快速解决方案。
So if it is not the case that there is a value for the name field,
所以如果姓名字段没有值，
just assume that there's a failure.
就假设出现了错误。
So how can I test this?
那么我该如何测试呢？
Let me go back to the other tab.
让我回到另一个标签页。
Let me go ahead and not type in my name and click Register.
让我不输入我的名字，然后点击注册。
And notice-- well, OK, I need to get rid of the required
然后你会注意到 - 好的，我需要去掉 required 属性，
if I actually want to see this thing go through.
如果我想让它提交。
So you know what?
所以，你知道吗？
Let's just change the template.
让我们改变一下模板。
Let's get rid of that so I don't have to hack into it
让我们摆脱它，这样我就不用再入侵它了
and delete things manually.
手动删除内容。
So let me reload the form.
所以让我重新加载表单。
Let me not type a name.
让我不输入姓名。
Click register.
点击注册。
And, oh, dang it.
而且，哦，该死。
405, Method Not Allowed.
405，方法不允许。
What's the fix for this in my app.py?
我的 app.py 中的修复方法是什么？
What line number needs to change?
哪一行需要更改？
Yeah, over there.
是的，在那边。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众： [听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, I need to allow both or at least POST at this point.
戴维·马兰：是的，我需要允许这两种方法，或者至少允许 POST 方法。
So I'll keep it more restrictive.
所以我会把它限制得更严格。
So methods equals and then in a list, quote, unquote,
所以 methods 等于，然后在一个列表中，引号，引号，
POST because that's what I'm using in my template as the method.
POST，因为这是我在模板中使用的那个方法。
All right, let's try again.
好的，让我们再试一次。
I'm going to go back.
我要返回。
I'm going to not type a name, and I'm going to click Register.
我不输入姓名，然后点击注册。
OK, so we caught the fact that the name was not provided.
好的，所以我们发现了没有提供姓名的事实。
Let's now go back and try again and actually cooperate.
现在让我们返回并再次尝试，并真正配合。
David, Register, OK, now internal server error.
戴维，注册，好的，现在内部服务器错误。
So something's gone even worse here.
所以这里有些事情变得更糟了。
And, unfortunately, you're going to start to see
不幸的是，你将在接下来的几周里开始看到
this over the next couple of weeks.
这种现象。
This is like Python and the web's equivalent of segmentation fault.
这就像 Python 和 web 中的段错误一样。
It's a different issue, but it's going to hurt just the same, unfortunately.
这是一个不同的问题，但不幸的是，它会造成同样的伤害。
So let's go back to VS Code here.
所以让我们回到这里的 VS Code。
Nothing seems to have gone wrong, but that's because I've hidden my terminal.
似乎没有任何错误，但这是因为我隐藏了我的终端。
Let me open my terminal window, and, oh, OK, so
让我打开我的终端窗口，哦，好的，所以
it looks like I made a crazy number of mistakes here somehow.
看来我在这里犯了很多错误。
But let me go ahead and focus on--
但让我继续关注 -
and the formatting's a little weird for some reason.
而且格式有些奇怪。
Here we go.
好了。
It's a little cryptic at first glance, but here's
乍一看有点难以理解，但这里就是
the most important line of output.
最重要的输出行。
The view function for, quote, unquote, "Register" did not
"注册" 的视图函数没有
return a valid response.
返回有效的响应。
So you're not going to see this one too often
所以你不太可能经常看到这个
most likely unless you do what I did, which was you didn't have an else.
除非你像我一样，没有 else 语句。
You didn't handle the situation where there is a name
你没有处理存在姓名的情况
and something should've come back.
应该返回一些东西。
So maybe I could do this.
所以也许我可以这样做。
By default, I could just say something like success as a catch
默认情况下，我可以简单地用 success 作为 catch
all even though I've not done anything useful yet.
尽管我还没有做任何有用的事情。
Let me try this again.
让我再试一次。
Let me go back.
让我返回。
David is typed in.
输入了 David。
No sport, Register.
没有运动，注册。
OK, so now I'm making progress again.
好的，现在我又在取得进展了。
So just like week one stuff, I make sure I'm always returning some value,
就像第一周的代码一样，我确保我总是返回一些值，
whether it's success or failure in this case.
在本例中，无论是成功还是失败。
All right, let's do something a little more interesting, though.
好吧，让我们做一些更有趣的事情。
I could do this.
我可以这样做。
How about elif not request.form.get sport.
elif not request.form.get sport 怎么样？
I could similarly return failure.
我可以类似地返回 failure。
But this is a little silly to have two nearly identical conditionals.
但有两个几乎相同的条件语句有点傻。
So, actually, let me just tighten this up.
所以，实际上，让我把它紧凑一些。
Let me go ahead and, instead, get rid of those two lines
让我继续，而不是删除这两行
and maybe just do something like this in Python or not request.form.get sport.
也许只是在 Python 中做这样的事情，或者不是 request.form.get sport。
This is maybe the tightest way just to ask two questions that are essentially
这可能是最紧凑的方式，只需要问两个本质上
the same but for two different keys.
相同但针对两个不同键的问题。
But returning, quote, unquote, "failure"'s a little weak.
但返回 "failure" 有点弱。
That's not a valid web page.
那不是一个有效的网页。
It's literally the word failure.
它就是 failure 这个词。
So maybe we do this, render_template, quote, unquote, "failure.html".
所以也许我们这样做，render_template，引号，引号，"failure.html"。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
Down here, render_template success.html.
这里，render_template success.html。
So we actually send the browser a valid web page, not just
所以我们实际上向浏览器发送了一个有效的网页，而不仅仅是
a single English word.
一个英文单词。
Of course, we're going to need those templates.
当然，我们需要这些模板。
So let me go in and do something like this.
所以让我进去做这样的事情。
If I go into, how about, my terminal window.
如果我进入，我的终端窗口怎么样。
I need another terminal because Flask is still running in that one.
我需要另一个终端，因为 Flask 还在那个终端中运行。
Let me go into froshims and let me do code of templates success.html.
让我进入 froshims 并让我做 templates success.html 的代码。
I'm going to save a few keystrokes and copy-paste all that stuff from index.
我要保存一些按键并从 index 中复制粘贴所有这些东西。
But I'm going to delete most of it.
但我将删除大部分内容。
And I'm just going to keep it super simple today.
我今天只是把它变得超级简单。
You are registered.
您已注册。
And then-- well, really, not really because we're
然后 - 嗯，实际上，不是，因为我们
not going to bother doing anything yet with the user's input.
现在不打算理会用户的输入。
Let me do something similar now for failure.
现在让我对 failure 做类似的事情。
So code templates failure.html.
所以 templates failure.html 的代码。
I'm going to copy-paste the same thing.
我要复制粘贴相同的内容。
And now I'm going to say the opposite, You are not registered.
现在我要说相反的话，您没有注册。
But I'm not going to be very useful, and I'm not
但我不会很有用，而且我不会
going to even yet tell the user what they have done wrong.
现在就告诉用户他们做错了什么。
But at least now we have the beginnings of a froshims app.
但至少现在我们有了 froshims 应用的雏形。
So let me go back, reload everything.
所以让我返回，重新加载所有内容。
Let me not cooperate at all and click Register.
让我完全不配合，然后点击注册。
OK, so you are not registered because of some failure.
好的，所以您没有注册，因为遇到了一些错误。
I'll type in my name.
我输入我的姓名。
OK, let's at least do that much.
好的，至少做这些吧。
I'm still not registered.
我仍然没有注册。
Let's go back.
让我们返回。
Let's leave David and choose soccer.
让我们离开 David 并选择足球。
Now, OK, now you are registered.
现在，好的，现在您已注册。
So I got the success template instead.
所以，我得到了 success 模板。
All right, so that seems to be better progress or at least the beginnings
好吧，所以这似乎是更好的进展，或者至少是一个
of an actually useful application.
真正有用的应用程序的开始。
But let's actually do more validation.
但让我们实际进行更多验证。
Why?
为什么？
Because notice what the human could still do.
因为注意人类仍然可以做什么。
Suppose that, out of principle, you really
假设，出于原则，你真的
want to register for a different sport.
想注册一个不同的运动。
So you're not a fan of soccer.
所以你不喜欢足球。
You want American football.
你想要美式足球。
So let's right-click or Control-click on that.
所以让我们右键单击或按住Control键单击它。
Choose Inspect.
选择检查。
And you can even do this client side.
你甚至可以在客户端这样做。
Let me write click on the Select menu.
让我右键单击“选择”菜单。
In Chrome, let me select Edit as HTML.
在Chrome中，让我选择“以HTML编辑”。
You can start adding any HTML you want.
你可以开始添加任何你想要的HTML。
So let me add an option football close option enter.
所以让我添加一个选项“足球”，然后关闭选项并按回车键。
And, aha, now you have to support football as well.
啊哈，现在你也必须支持足球了。
Of course, this is going to work because if I type in David and football
当然，这会起作用，因为如果我在“姓名”中输入“David”和“足球”，
and Register even though I'm not doing anything with the response,
然后点击“注册”，即使我没有对响应做任何操作，
I got through that validation filter because I was just
我通过了那个验证过滤器，因为我只是
checking that there's an actual value.
检查是否有实际的值。
So this is now no longer really correct because some annoying first year who's
所以现在这不再正确了，因为一些烦人的大一新生正在
just taken CS50 is now going to do something
刚学习了CS50，现在就要对我的网页应用程序做一些
like this to my web application.
像这样的操作。
And we're going to have bogus data in the database, ultimately.
最终，我们的数据库中将会有虚假数据。
So how do you defend against this properly when it really is that easy?
所以，当它真的这么容易的时候，你如何正确地防御它？
And, honestly, as soon as you put a web application on the internet,
老实说，一旦你把网页应用程序放到互联网上，
bad things will happen to it because people with too much free time.
就会有不好的事情发生，因为人们有太多空闲时间。
So how do we defend against it?
所以我们如何防御它？
What would be a better approach?
有什么更好的方法吗？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice, so add another conditional such
大卫·马兰：不错，所以添加另一个条件，例如
that the only things allowed are the sports we actually
只允许我们实际上提供的运动。
are offering this semester.
在这一学期提供的运动。
And, in fact, you know what?
实际上，你知道吗？
We can take this one step further.
我们可以更进一步。
The fact that I hardcoded into my form, my select menu, those three sports--
我将这三种运动硬编码到我的表单中，我的下拉菜单中——
it'd be nice to maybe factor out those sports altogether
把这些运动全部提取出来，这样会比较好。
so that I have one authoritative list that's used for generating the form
这样我就可以有一个权威列表，用于生成表单
and also validating the user's input.
并验证用户的输入。
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
In app.py, let me go in here.
在app.py中，让我进入这里。
And I can put this, how about, the top of my file, to be conventional.
我可以在文件顶部放置它，这样比较规范。
I'm going to create a global variable called sports.
我将创建一个名为“sports”的全局变量。
By convention, in Python, I'm going to make it all uppercase even though that
按照惯例，在Python中，我将它全部大写，即使这
doesn't mean anything functional.
在功能上没有任何意义。
There's no const keyword in Python.
Python中没有const关键字。
So it's more on the honor system that no one else should touch this.
所以更多的是靠自觉，其他人不应该碰它。
But, inside of my list here, let's go ahead
但是，在我的列表中，让我们继续
and do only the official three, basketball, soccer,
只做官方的三个，篮球、足球，
and ultimate Frisbee.
和极限飞盘。
So now I have a Python list of values that it
所以现在我有一个Python值列表，它
would be nice to use to generate that other form.
可以用它来生成另一个表单。
So this is maybe nonobvious.
所以这可能不太明显。
But I think it's just an application of past ideas.
但我认为这只是对以前想法的应用。
What if I do this?
如果我这样做呢？
What if I pass into my index.html template
如果我将它传递到我的index.html模板中
a placeholder called sports and set it equal to the value
一个名为“sports”的占位符，并将它设置为该值
of that global variable sports.
全局变量“sports”的值。
Now, I'm trying to adhere to best practices.
现在，我正在努力遵循最佳实践。
The placeholder is called sports in lowercase.
占位符名为“sports”，是小写。
But the actual variable I called all uppercase just
但我实际调用的变量全部是大写，只是
to make clear that it's a constant even though that's on the honor system.
为了清楚地表明它是一个常量，即使这只是靠自觉。
But this too is conventional.
但这也很常规。
This is a Pythonic way or a Flask-centric way to do this.
这是Pythonic方法或Flask-centric方法。
But now, in index.html, this is where Jinja gets interesting.
但是现在，在index.html中，Jinja就变得有趣了。
This lightweight syntax for using placeholders
这种使用占位符的轻量级语法
gets interesting because I can now do something like this.
变得有趣，因为我现在可以做这样的操作。
I'm going to delete all three of the sports
我将删除所有三个运动，
but not the disabled option, which is just the placeholder text, inside
但不是“禁用”选项，它只是占位符文本，在
of this select menu.
这个下拉菜单中。
Now I'm going to do this.
现在我将做以下操作。
Just like Python, I'm going to say for sport
就像Python一样，我将说“for sport”
in sports using the curly brace notation and the percent signs, which
在“sports”中，使用花括号和百分号，它们是
are Jinja specific even though Jinja and Python use almost the same syntax.
Jinja特有的，尽管Jinja和Python使用几乎相同的语法。
And that's one of the upsides of it.
这是它的一大优势。
You're not learning two things.
你没有学习两件事。
You're learning 1.1 new things.
你学习了1.1件新事物。
endfor, which looks stupid, but this is a convention
“endfor”，看起来很愚蠢，但这是
in a lot of languages to literally say end and the name of the keyword
许多语言中的惯例，就是说“end”和要结束的关键字的名称，
that you are ending with no space.
之间没有空格。
Inside of this Jinja loop, I'm going to write an option element once, option.
在这个Jinja循环中，我将写一个option元素，option。
And then, inside of the two option tags, I'm
然后，在两个option标签内，我将
going to do my placeholder syntax with two curly braces
使用我的占位符语法，用两个花括号
and just say sport like this.
然后就说“sport”就行了。
And if I now go back into my browser tab and hit back here
如果我现在回到浏览器标签页，然后点击后退按钮，
and I reload the page, notice that I still
然后我重新加载页面，注意我仍然
have a dropdown that's still automatically populated
有一个下拉菜单，它仍然自动填充
because indeed if I go to View page source and look at the actual HTML,
因为实际上，如果我查看页面源代码并查看实际的HTML，
there's some extra weird whitespace, but that's
有一些额外的奇怪空白，但那是
because I hit Enter in my template.
因为我在模板中按了回车键。
And it's generating literally what I put inside of that Jinja tag.
它正在生成我放在那个Jinja标签里面的内容。
It's generating that list of sports.
它正在生成那个运动列表。
And it turns out--
事实证明——
I'm going to do this just to be thorough.
为了完整起见，我将这样做。
It turns out that the option element technically lets
事实证明，option元素在技术上允许你
you specify a value for that sport.
为该运动指定一个值。
Often, they're one and the same.
通常，它们是一样的。
What the human sees is what the value of the option is.
人类看到的就是option的值。
It's kind of like the a href thing in the world of URLs.
它就像 URL 世界中的 a href 标签一样。
But this is not going to change the functionality.
但这不会改变功能。
But it's going to do this.
但它会做这件事。
If I reload now and I View page source, this is maybe a more common way
如果我现在重新加载并查看页面源代码，这可能是一个更常见的方法
to see options where, in orange, in my browser,
查看选项，在我的浏览器中，橙色部分
is what the server is going to receive.
是服务器将接收到的内容。
In white is what the human's going to see.
白色部分是用户将看到的。
They don't have to be one and the same for reasons we'll soon see.
它们不必相同，原因我们很快就会看到。
But what's nice now is that if I do actually
但现在好的地方是，如果我真的
want to officially support American football, I can go in here,
想正式支持美式足球，我可以在这里，
add "football", quote, unquote, to my list,
将 "football" 添加到我的列表中，
go back to the form, reload, and voila.
返回表单，重新加载，瞧！
Now I have a list of all four.
现在我有四个项目的列表。
But I haven't done the second side of what you proposed,
但我还没有做你提议的第二件事，
which is actually validate those sports.
那就是实际验证这些运动项目。
So let me do that.
所以我做一下。
Let me go over to app.py.
我到 app.py 文件。
And, in app.py-- and we'll no longer support football there--
在 app.py 文件中，我们不再支持足球了——
let's do this in my registration route.
我们可以在我的注册路由中做这件事。
So, instead of just checking, is there a value?
所以，我们不再只是检查是否存在值，
And the whole point of using not is kind of like in C
使用 not 的关键在于，它就像在 C 语言中一样
where you use an exclamation point to invert the meaning.
使用感叹号来反转含义。
So if it's empty but it's not, then it's-- the whole value is true.
所以，如果它为空但又不为空，那么它的整个值就是真。
Let's get rid of this line.
我们去掉这一行。
And let's instead do something like this.
我们改成做这样的事。
How about if not request.form.get name.
如果 request.form.get name 不为空的话
So let's still just check for a name.
所以我们仍然只检查是否包含名称。
Or request.form.get, quote, unquote, "sport" is not in the sports list.
或者 request.form.get 的“sport”不在运动项目列表中。
Now go ahead and say there's a failure.
现在说出现了错误。
So what does this mean?
这意味着什么呢？
If I go back to the browser and reload, I now see only three sports.
如果我回到浏览器并重新加载，现在我只看到三种运动项目。
And I think this will work,
我认为这会起作用，
OK, David.
好的，大卫。
We'll register, say, for soccer, Register, and it seems to work.
我们注册，比如足球，注册，它似乎可以正常工作。
But if some hacker comes along and really
但如果一些黑客来这里，真的
wants to register for American football, I'll right-click there.
想注册美式足球，我会在那里右键单击。
I'll inspect this.
我将检查它。
I'm going to hack the form and add a bogus option
我要攻击表单并添加一个虚假选项
at the very end just for myself.
在最后，只为了我自己。
And, down here, I'm going to say option value equals, quote, unquote,
在下面，我将说 option value 等于，双引号，
"football".
“football”。
And then, inside of the option, I'm going
然后，在 option 内部，我将
to say football just to be consistent even though they're one and the same.
说足球，为了保持一致，尽管它们是一样的。
Save that.
保存。
Close the developer tools.
关闭开发者工具。
Choose the hacked option.
选择被攻击的选项。
Register, but, no, we caught it this time.
注册，但是，不，这次我们抓住了。
So this is hugely important.
所以，这一点非常重要。
And there are so many darn websites in the real world where
现实世界中有很多网站，
the programmers either don't know or don't care
程序员要么不知道，要么不在乎
to actually validate stuff server side.
实际在服务器端验证信息。
This is how servers quite often get hacked.
这就是服务器经常被攻击的方式。
You might have client-side validation using HTML or JavaScript.
你可能使用 HTML 或 JavaScript 进行客户端验证。
And it looks nice.
看起来不错。
It's immediate.
它很直接。
It's very pretty and graphical.
它非常漂亮和图形化。
But if you're not also paranoically checking on the server,
但如果你没有在服务器上进行偏执地检查，
this is indeed how servers get hacked.
这确实就是服务器被攻击的方式。
Or, at least in the best case here, your data set
或者，至少在最好的情况下，你的数据集
is sort of polluted with sports that you're not actually going to offer.
被你实际上不会提供的运动项目污染了。
So this is not a very harmful attack, but it's
所以这并不是一种非常有害的攻击，但它
representative of what kind of actions can be taken on your server
代表了在你的服务器上可以采取的行动类型
if you don't distrust the user.
如果你不信任用户。
So, unfortunately, this is kind of a negative day.
所以，不幸的是，这是有点消极的一天。
Never, ever trust user input.
永远不要信任用户输入。
We saw that already with SQL and injection attacks.
我们已经在 SQL 和注入攻击中看到了这一点。
All right, any other questions?
好了，还有其他问题吗？
Any questions thus far on this?
到目前为止，对此有任何问题吗？
Otherwise, we'll add a bit of spice in just a moment.
否则，我们过一会儿会添加一些调味料。
No?
没有？
All right, well, just to show you an alternative to this,
好的，为了向你展示一种替代方法，
let me change the GUI, the Graphical User Interface, slightly.
让我稍微改变一下 GUI，即图形用户界面。
Drop-down menus pretty compelling here.
下拉菜单在这里很有说服力。
But there's other techniques.
但还有其他技巧。
And we won't dwell on HTML tags, which you can pick up largely online.
我们不会过多关注 HTML 标签，你可以在网上找到很多关于它的信息。
But let me go into maybe index.html just to show you
但让我进入 index.html 文件，向你展示
one different approach here.
一种不同的方法。
And if you really like radio buttons, the little circles that
如果你真的喜欢单选按钮，那些小圆圈，
are mutually exclusive-- this is a throwback to radios, before my time,
是互斥的——这是一种对无线电的回归，在我那个时代之前，
in cars where, when you pushed the button for one radio station,
在汽车里，当你按下某个电台的按钮时，
it would pop out the buttons for another, essentially,
它会弹出另一个按钮，本质上是
for your favorite channels.
为了你的收藏频道。
Radio buttons are, by definition, therefore, mutually exclusive.
因此，根据定义，单选按钮是互斥的。
So if I want to see those radio buttons and not a select menu,
所以，如果我想看到那些单选按钮，而不是下拉菜单，
let me go into index.html.
让我进入 index.html 文件。
And, instead of this select menu, let me actually delete that.
然后，代替这个下拉菜单，我实际上删除它。
And even though this isn't going to be super pretty, let me do this.
尽管这看起来不太漂亮，但我这样做。
for sport in sports, just as before, endfor, just preemptively.
就像之前一样，for sport in sports，endfor，先做准备。
Inside of this Jinja loop, I'm going to do this.
在这个 Jinja 循环中，我要做这样的事。
I'm going to do an actual input tag.
我要添加一个真正的 input 标签。
But it's not going to be text.
但它不是文本。
But the name of this tag--
但这个标签的名称——
of this element is going to be sport.
这个元素的名称将是 sport。
The type of this element is going to be radio for radio buttons.
这个元素的类型将是 radio，用于单选按钮。
And the value of this button is going to be whatever that sport is.
这个按钮的值将是该运动项目。
But what the human is going to see next to the radio button to the right
但用户在单选按钮右边将看到的是
is the same thing, the name of the sport.
一样的东西，运动项目的名称。
So this is going to look a little different.
所以看起来有点不同。
And it is going to look ugly in my black and white viewport here with no CSS.
在我的黑白视图中，没有CSS，它看起来会很丑陋。
But it does speak to how you can change the user interface just using
但这说明你可以只使用
different building blocks.
不同的构建块来改变用户界面。
Let me reload.
让我重新加载一下。
And, OK, it's probably not the right call here
好吧，这可能不是这里正确的选择
because it's just kind of making things ugly.
因为它只是让东西看起来很丑。
But it's as simple as that because if I now click on this or this or this,
但就这么简单，因为如果我现在点击这个，或者这个，或者这个，
they're indeed mutually exclusive.
它们确实是互斥的。
However, suppose that you want to allow the particularly athletic first years
然而，假设你想要允许特别有运动天赋的大一新生
to sign up for not one but two sports or all three.
报名参加一项以上甚至三项运动。
In no case now can you support that right now.
现在你无法支持这种情况。
The workaround now for a bad website would
现在，对于一个糟糕的网站，解决方法是
be, oh, just go register twice, or go register three times.
哦，只需注册两次，或者注册三次。
It's not a huge deal because you just hit back.
这不是什么大问题，因为你只需点击后退。
And then you change the dropdown and submit.
然后你更改下拉菜单并提交。
You hit back you change the dropdown and submit.
你点击后退，更改下拉菜单并提交。
But that's just bad design.
但这仅仅是糟糕的设计。
Surely, we can do better than that.
当然，我们可以做得比这更好。
So, in fact, let's make one change here and use checkboxes.
所以，实际上，让我们在这里做一个改变，使用复选框。
And if you've never really thought hard about this in the web,
如果你从未在网页上认真考虑过这个问题，
radio buttons and checkboxes have this distinct property
单选按钮和复选框具有这种独特的属性
where the former is mutually exclusive, and the latter
前者是互斥的，而后者
is inclusive whereby you can check 0 or more of those boxes collectively.
是包含式的，你可以集体选中这些复选框中的零个或多个。
So if I actually just go into that same template
所以如果我实际上只是进入同一个模板
and change the type of this input from radio to checkbox
并将这个输入的类型从单选改为复选框
and then go back to the browser and reload,
然后返回浏览器并重新加载，
you immediately get what you and I see in the real world as checkboxes.
你立刻就会看到你和我在现实世界中所看到的复选框。
And the upside of this is that you can check now 0 or more of them.
而这样做的优势在于，你现在可以选中零个或多个复选框。
But the catch-- and this is subtle--
但问题是，这是微妙的，
the catch with our code right now is that we're only expecting one value.
我们目前的代码只期望一个值。
So it's a minor fix, but it's a useful thing to know.
所以这是一个小修复，但这是一个有用的东西需要知道。
If I go back to app.py, if I actually want to get all of the sports
如果我回到app.py，如果我实际上想要获取所有的运动
from the users, I'm going to have to change my validation slightly.
从用户那里，我将不得不稍微改变我的验证。
So I'm going to do this.
所以我会这样做。
I'm going to check for the presence of a name as before.
我将像以前一样检查名称是否存在。
But then I'm going to use a loop to validate the sports because I
但随后，我将使用一个循环来验证运动，因为我
don't want them to slip, like football, back into the list
不希望它们，例如足球，滑回列表中
even if it's not there.
即使它不在那里。
So I'm going to say this in Python.
所以我会在 Python 中这样说。
for each sport in request.form.getall.
对于 request.form.getall 中的每个运动。
If you know it's a checkbox, you want to get all of the checked values, not one,
如果你知道它是复选框，你想要获取所有选中的值，而不是一个，
for the sport parameter, then go ahead and do this.
对于运动参数，那么继续执行此操作。
If the current sport is not in that sports list up top,
如果当前运动不在上面的运动列表中，
then go ahead and return render_template failure.html.
那么继续执行并返回 render_template failure.html。
Did I make a mistake here?
我在这里犯错了吗？
I think we're good there.
我认为我们那里很好。
So we're checking against every value that was checked on the form.
所以我们正在检查表单上被选中的每个值。
Is it actually valid?
它实际上有效吗？
And so now if I go in here, reload, type in my name David, and I'll
所以现在如果我到这里，重新加载，输入我的名字 David，然后我会
just check one of them, for instance, because I've not hacked the form
只选中其中一个，例如，因为我没有破解表单
and added something bogus like football.
并添加了一些虚假的东西，比如足球。
Maybe someone was alluding to this.
也许有人暗示过这一点。
I see now an error.
我现在看到一个错误。
So let's do this together.
所以让我们一起做这个。
Not sure what I did wrong.
我不确定我做错了什么。
I'm going to open up my terminal and go to here.
我将打开我的终端并转到此处。
And, oh, interesting, my spacing's a little weird here.
而且，哦，有趣的是，我的间距在这里有点奇怪。
But attribute error.
但属性错误。
Immutable dictionary has no attribute getall.
不可变字典没有 getall 属性。
So this is me lying to you.
所以这是我在骗你。
I don't think so.
我不认为是这样。
But [INAUDIBLE], are you here?
但是 [听不清]，你在吗？
Did Flask change since I last did this?
自从我上次这样做以来，Flask 有变化吗？
No.
没有。
OK, so Flask post form getall.
好吧，所以 Flask 提交表单 getall。
All right, here we go.
好了，我们开始吧。
About 2012, this is probably out of date.
大约 2012 年，这可能已经过时了。
But ah.
但是啊。
You know, that's not a bad idea, OK.
你知道，那不是一个坏主意，好吧。
All right, OK, in Flask, how do I get all of the values
好了，好的，在 Flask 中，我如何获取所有值
from an HTML input of type checkbox from request.form?
来自 request.form 中类型为复选框的 HTML 输入？
Well, this is horrifying.
好吧，这太可怕了。
getlist!
getlist！
Damn it, OK.
该死，好吧。
What a good duck.
真是个好鸭子。
All right, so-- all right, so we'll rewind in time.
好了，所以，好了，所以我们将倒退回时间。
So thank you.
所以谢谢您。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So that's a good lesson.
所以这是一个很好的教训。
Just do as I do.
照我做就行了。
All right, so getlist will get you a list of all of those values.
好了，所以 getlist 会给你一个所有这些值的列表。
So now if I go ahead and register as David,
所以现在如果我继续以 David 的身份注册，
click just soccer without injecting something
只点击足球，不注入任何东西
like American football and Register, now I'm,
比如美式足球，然后注册，现在我
in fact, registered but not really, not really in the sense
实际上，已经注册了，但实际上没有，在某种意义上还没有
that we haven't actually done anything with the data.
我们没有真正对数据做任何事情。
So this is to say, ultimately, that there's a lot of these building blocks,
所以，最终，这意味着有许多这些构建块，
not only in HTML, which is mostly a throwback to last week but also now,
不仅在 HTML 中，它主要是对上周的回顾，而且现在，
in Flask, where you can process all of those building blocks
在 Flask 中，你可以处理所有这些构建块
and take control over what up, until now,
并控制直到现在
is usually the domain of Google or the websites that you actually use.
通常是 Google 或者你实际使用的网站的领域。
Now you actually have more of the building blocks via which
现在你实际上拥有更多构建块，通过它们
to implement these things yourself.
自己实现这些东西。
So let's go ahead and add some final features to froshims
所以让我们继续为 Froshims 添加一些最终的功能
here where we're actually doing something with the results.
在这里，我们实际上对结果做了一些事情。
And, for this, I'm going to open up a version in advance.
而且，为此，我将提前打开一个版本。
So I'm going to go over to VS Code here.
所以我要转到这里的 VS Code。
And let me go ahead and close these tabs but go into my second terminal window.
让我继续关闭这些标签，但进入我的第二个终端窗口。
And I'm going to go into today's src9 directory.
我要进入到今天的 src9 目录。
And I'm going to go into version 4 of froshims, which has
我将进入 froshims 的版本 4，其中包含
everything we just did plus a bit more.
我们刚刚做的一切，外加一些额外的东西。
In particular, I'm going to go ahead and do this.
特别是，我将继续这样做。
I'm going to show you app.py, which, additionally,
我将向大家展示 app.py，它还
has some comments throughout.
包含一些贯穿始终的注释。
But, in app.py, what you'll notice is that, after all of my validation,
但是在 app.py 中，你会注意到，在我完成所有验证之后，
I'm actually got a couple of new features here.
我实际上在这里添加了一些新功能。
It's a little weak in terms of UI to just tell the user failure.
仅仅告诉用户失败，在用户界面方面有点弱。
You are not registered.
您尚未注册。
That's all my template previously did.
这就是我之前使用的模板所做的全部内容。
But what if I borrow an idea from my index template where all of this time,
但是，如果我从我的 index 模板中借鉴一个想法，在所有这段时间里，
for hello and froshims, I've been passing in input.
对于 hello 和 froshims，我一直都在传递输入。
So what if I do this?
那么，如果我这样做呢？
Let me show you.
让我来展示给你看。
In templates, failure.html-- or, rather, let's see, in templates, error.html.
在模板中，failure.html——或者，更确切地说，让我们来看看，在模板中，error.html。
So notice this, I can make the beginnings
所以请注意，我可以做出
of a common format for an error page.
错误页面的通用格式的开端。
So, in error.html of this fourth example,
所以，在这个第四个例子中的 error.html，
I've just got some big, bold error message at the top.
我仅仅在顶部加了一些大而粗的错误信息。
But I have a paragraph tag inside of which
但我有一个段落标签，在它里面
is a placeholder for an error message.
是一个错误信息占位符。
And then I've gone one step further just because and put a happy cat or grumpy
然后，我仅仅是为了更进一步，添加了一只快乐的猫或一只生气的猫
cat as an image to let you down easy that something has gone wrong.
作为图像，让你更容易接受发生了错误这件事。
But this is like now every website where there's generally some customized error
但是现在每个网站上都有一点定制的错误
message when something has gone wrong or when you have not
信息，当发生错误或当你没有
cooperated with the rules of the form.
遵守表单的规则时。
So what am I doing instead?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Instead of rendering failure.html very generically,
与其以非常通用的方式渲染 failure.html，
I'm rendering this new template error.html.
我将渲染这个新的模板 error.html。
And I'm passing in a custom message.
并且我传递了一个自定义信息。
Why?
为什么？
Because now, in my app.py, my logic, I can actually say,
因为现在，在我的 app.py 中，我的逻辑，我实际上可以这样说，
you're missing your name.
你漏掉了你的名字。
You're missing a sport.
你漏掉了你的运动项目。
Or I can tell the human what the error, which is much better user interface.
或者，我可以告诉用户发生了什么错误，这在用户界面方面要好得多。
Down here, though, on this new line, here's
不过，在这条新行上，这里就是
where I'm now beginning to actually register registrants.
我开始真正注册登记人的地方。
What's the easiest way to do this?
怎么做最简单呢？
Well, let me scroll to the top of this file.
好吧，让我滚动到这个文件的最顶部。
And you'll see that, in addition, to a big list of sports,
你会看到，除了一个大的运动项目列表之外，
I also have an empty dictionary initially of registrants.
我还初始设置了一个空的登记人字典。
Why?
为什么？
Well, dictionaries are this nice Swiss army knife, key-value pair, key, value,
好吧，字典就像一把精巧的瑞士军刀，键值对，键，值，
key, value.
键，值。
Names could be keys.
名字可以是键。
And maybe sports could be values, at least
也许运动项目可以是值，至少
if I'm supporting just single sports.
如果我仅仅支持单项运动。
So I could have a fancier structure, but this
所以我可以有一个更精巧的结构，但这个
seems sufficient, two columns, key, value, for name, sport, name, sport,
似乎足够了，两列，键，值，用于名字，运动项目，名字，运动项目，
and so forth.
等等。
So how do I put a person's name into that global dictionary?
那么，如何将一个人的名字放到那个全局字典中呢？
Well, I'll use the syntax from week six, registrants bracket name
好吧，我将使用第六周的语法，登记人方括号名字
equals sport that associates that value with that key.
等于运动项目，将该值与该键关联起来。
And, now, what you'll see in that I've added a new route /registrants.
现在，你会看到，我已经添加了一个新的路由 /registrants。
And this is where things get interesting.
而这就是事情变得有趣的地方。
If I look at this premade route as you will too,
如果我查看这个预先制作好的路由，就像你一样，
as you look at code that's been written for you in the weeks to come,
当你查看未来几周为你编写的代码时，
well, this sort of invites me to look at registrants.html.
那么，这就会促使我查看 registrants.html。
Why?
为什么？
Apparently, this registrants.html template
显然，这个 registrants.html 模板
is being passed this global dictionary.
正在传递这个全局字典。
How might I use that?
我该如何使用它呢？
Well, let me go into VS Code's terminal.
好吧，让我进入 VS Code 的终端。
Let me take a look at registrants.html.
让我看看 registrants.html。
And, interesting, we haven't used this HTML much.
有趣的是，我们并没有经常使用这个 HTML。
I used it super briefly last week.
我上周非常简短地使用过它。
This is an HTML table.
这是一个 HTML 表格。
It's not going to look super pretty because I'm not
它看起来不会非常漂亮，因为我没有
using bootstrap or CSS more generally.
使用 Bootstrap 或更一般的 CSS。
But notice that, in the table's head, there's
但是请注意，在表格的头部，
name and sport from left to right in the two columns.
名字和运动项目从左到右位于两列中。
And then, in the table body or tbody, notice
然后，在表格主体或 tbody 中，请注意
that I have a whole bunch of tr, tr, tr, one for every registrant in that Jinja
我有许多 tr、tr、tr，每个在 Jinja 中的登记人都有一个。
loop.
循环。
Each of the cells, the table datas have the person's name.
每个单元格，表格数据都有该人的名字。
And then if you go inside of that dictionary and look up the name,
然后，如果你进入到那个字典中并查找名字，
you get the value thereof, so name, sport, name, sport.
你将获得它的值，所以名字，运动项目，名字，运动项目。
And the route, of course, again, is just this, render registrants.html
当然，路由仍然是这个，渲染 registrants.html
by passing in that dictionary.
通过传递那个字典。
So what is registrants.html?
那么 registrants.html 是什么呢？
It's just this.
它就是这个。
So I think if we go and run this version of the application,
所以，我认为，如果我们运行这个版本的应用程序，
we have some nice new features.
我们将拥有一些不错的新功能。
Let me go ahead and do Flask--
让我继续做 Flask——
let me kill Flask in the other window just so it's not using the same port.
让我在另一个窗口中关闭 Flask，这样它就不会使用相同的端口。
Let me do flask run inside of froshims4.
让我在 froshims4 中运行 flask。
So far, so good.
到目前为止，一切顺利。
Let me go over to my other tab.
让我转到另一个选项卡。
Let me reload.
让我重新加载。
So I get the latest HTML.
所以，我得到了最新的 HTML。
I'm going to go ahead and type in something like David
我将输入类似于 David 之类的内容
but select no sport using radio buttons.
但使用单选按钮选择没有运动项目。
So, again, you can only pick one.
所以，再次说明，你只能选择一个。
And now not only am I seeing one grumpy cat there.
现在，我不仅在那里看到了一只生气的猫。
It's also telling me at the top that I'm missing the sport.
它还在顶部告诉我，我漏掉了运动项目。
Conversely, if I reload the page, don't give my name.
反过来，如果我重新加载页面，不输入我的名字。
But do give the sport and register.
但输入运动项目并注册。
Now you see that I'm missing name and not sport.
现在，你会看到我漏掉了名字，但没有漏掉运动项目。
So, again, the UI is not very pretty, but it has the building blocks
所以，再次强调，用户界面不是很好看，但它具备更适合的构建模块
of being much more appropriate.
变得更合适
Let me now cooperate on both fronts.
现在让我在这两个方面合作。
David wants to register for soccer, Register.
大卫想报名参加足球，注册。
And now notice where I am.
现在注意我在哪里。
Apparently, I got redirected to the registrants route,
显然，我被重定向到了注册者路由，
inside of which is this two column table.
里面是这个两列的表格。
It's not very interesting yet.
目前还不怎么有趣。
So let me go back to the form.
所以让我回到表单。
And let me register Carter, for instance,
让我注册卡特，例如，
for, say, basketball, Register.
例如，篮球，注册。
And now there's two of us.
现在我们有两个人了。
Let me actually go back to the form.
让我回到表单。
And let me register Yulia for ultimate Frisbee, Register.
让我注册尤利亚参加极限飞盘，注册。
Now there's three of us.
现在我们有三个了。
And, again, the CSS is ugly, but I do have an HTML table.
再次强调，CSS 很难看，但我确实有一个 HTML 表格。
And if I right-click and View page source,
如果我右键单击并查看页面源代码，
you'll see David, soccer; Carter, basketball; Yulia, ultimate Frisbee all
你会看到大卫、足球；卡特、篮球；尤利亚、极限飞盘都
as tr, tr, tr.
作为 tr、tr、tr。
So, again, if you now think about an app like Gmail in your inbox,
所以，再次强调，如果你现在想想像 Gmail 这样的收件箱应用程序，
odds are if your inbox is indeed a big table,
如果你的收件箱确实是一个大表格，
then it's probably tr, tr, tr, tr.
那么它可能是 tr、tr、tr、tr。
And Google is rendering all of that HTML dynamically
而谷歌正在动态渲染所有这些 HTML
based on all of the emails in some variable somewhere.
基于某处某个变量中的所有电子邮件。
Well, let me go back here and see, how did that redirect work?
好吧，让我回到这里看看，重定向是如何工作的？
Let's watch this a little more slowly.
让我们慢点看看。
Let me go up to the main form at slash.
让我回到斜杠上的主表单。
Let me type in David.
让我输入大卫。
Let me type in-- select soccer.
让我输入-- 选择足球。
And let me Zoom in to the URL.
让我放大 URL。
And notice that, when I submit this form,
注意，当我提交此表单时，
even though the action is /register, I'm indeed ending up at /registrants.
尽管操作是 /register，但我最终还是到了 /registrants。
So how is that actually happening?
那么这究竟是如何发生的？
Well, let me go back and do it one more time.
好吧，让我回到这里再做一次。
But, this time, let me open up Developer Tools.
但是，这次，让我打开开发者工具。
Let me go to the Network tab, which, recall, we played with last week.
让我转到网络选项卡，记得上周我们用过它。
And let me go ahead and do this again.
让我再次尝试。
So David, Soccer, and I'm going to click Register.
所以是大卫、足球，我要点击注册。
And now, notice, interesting, two routes were actually involved.
现在，注意，有趣的是，实际上涉及了两个路由。
The first one here is Register.
第一个是注册。
But notice if I go to headers, ah, 302 found.
但注意，如果我去标题，啊，302 找到。
302 indicated some kind of redirect.
302 表示某种重定向。
What's the redirect going to?
重定向到哪里？
Well, if I look-- scroll down here at response headers,
好吧，如果我看看-- 在这里向下滚动到响应标头，
there's a lot of stuff that's not interesting,
有很多东西不有趣，
but location was the one we cared about last week. /registrants, oh,
但是上周我们关心的是位置。/registrants，哦，
that's why the second request over here at left is actually /registrants.
这就是为什么左边第二个请求实际上是 /registrants。
And it is 200 OK because it's all of these basic building
它是 200 OK，因为它所有这些基本的构建
blocks from last week and now this.
块来自上周，现在又有了这个。
Where did that redirect come from?
重定向来自哪里？
Well, now you have the ability to do this.
现在你就可以做到这一点。
Notice that, in my register route, the last thing I said we had done
请注意，在我的注册路由中，我最后说我们已经完成了
was add the name and the value to this global dictionary.
就是将名称和值添加到这个全局字典中。
But the very last thing I did was redirect the user to the /registrants
但我最后做的是将用户重定向到 /registrants
route.
路由。
What is redirect?
什么是重定向？
Well, at the very top of this file, notice
好吧，在这个文件的顶部，请注意
that I proactively imported not just flask, render_template, and request.
我主动导入的不仅仅是 flask、render_template 和 request。
I also imported redirect this time, which
这次我还导入了重定向，它
is a function that comes with Flask that automatically issues the HTTP 302
是一个 Flask 附带的函数，它会自动发出 HTTP 302
redirect for you without you having to know anything about those numbers
为你进行重定向，而无需你了解任何关于这些数字的知识
or otherwise.
或其他。
Let's do one final example before we break for snacks.
在我们去吃零食之前，我们来做最后一个例子。
In this final example, froshims5, let's actually do something with SQL.
在这个最后的例子中，froshims5，让我们实际使用一下 SQL。
SQL, after all, allows us to persist the data because this version here,
SQL 毕竟允许我们持久化数据，因为这个版本，
with this global dictionary, what's the downside of using this global variable
用这个全局变量有什么缺点
to store all of our registrants?
来存储所有注册者？
What's the downside?
有什么缺点？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly, so, as soon as the server quits
大卫·马兰：没错，所以，服务器一旦退出
or if something goes wrong like maybe the power goes out,
或者如果出现问题，比如断电，
or we have multiple servers or something like that,
或者我们有多个服务器，或者类似的情况，
we'll lose the contents of that dictionary.
我们会丢失字典的内容。
And so that's not really good to store data
所以，这不是一个好办法来存储数据
that you care about in the computer's memory alone or RAM.
你关心，仅仅在计算机内存或 RAM 中。
You want to store it on disk using something like fopen and fwrite
你想要将它存储在磁盘上，使用类似 fopen 和 fwrite 的东西
and all of the file I/O stuff we talked about.
以及我们讨论过的一切文件 I/O 操作。
But, in week seven, recall, we introduced SQL.
但是，记得第七周，我们介绍了 SQL。
So that writes things to disk in a .db file.
这样就会将东西写入磁盘上的 .db 文件。
So let's actually do that with one final example.
所以，让我们用最后一个例子来实际操作一下。
Let me go ahead and close these tabs here in my terminal.
让我继续，关闭我在终端中的这些选项卡。
Let me go ahead and close the old version of froshims
让我继续，关闭 froshims 的旧版本
and go into froshims5 now.
现在进入 froshims5。
And, in this version, let me show you, in app.py, the following.
在这个版本中，让我在 app.py 中向你展示如下内容。
It's almost the same in terms of what we're importing from Flask.
就从 Flask 导入的内容而言，它几乎相同。
But I'm also going to import from CS50's library
但我也将从 CS50 的库中导入
a SQL function, which we used briefly when we wrote code
一个 SQL 函数，我们在编写代码时简要使用过它
in Python to talk to a SQLite database.
用 Python 与 SQLite 数据库进行交互。
This is the one example of a CS50 training wheel
这是 CS50 辅助工具的一个例子
that we actually do keep on deliberately through the end of the term
我们确实故意保留到学期结束
because it's actually just really annoying
因为它实际上真的很烦人
to use most third-party libraries with SQL in as user friendly a way.
以用户友好的方式使用大多数与 SQL 相关的第三方库。
You're welcome to, but I do think that, even though you shouldn't
你可以使用，但我认为，即使你不应该
be using get in getstring, getfloat anymore the SQL function's actually
再使用 getstring、getfloat 中的 get，SQL 函数实际上
pretty darn useful, I would say.
非常有用，我认为。
So how do we use this?
那么我们如何使用它呢？
Everything in this file so far is pretty much the same except for that import,
到目前为止，此文件中的所有内容都与之前相同，除了那个导入，
including these lines here.
包括这里面的这些行。
But notice that I am opening up a file called froshims.db.
但请注意，我正在打开一个名为 froshims.db 的文件。
And that's a database that's empty initially.
这是一个最初为空的数据库。
But it is in my account.
但它在我的账户中。
So, actually, let me do this.
所以，实际上，让我这样做。
Let me run sqlite3 on froshims.db.
让我在 froshims.db 上运行 sqlite3。
Let me increase the size of my terminal.
让我扩大我的终端窗口大小。
Hit Enter.
按回车键。
What can I type to see the structure of this database?
我能输入什么来查看这个数据库的结构？
Sorry.
抱歉。
Wait, what?
等等，什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, yes, thank you.
大卫·马兰：哦，是的，谢谢。
.schema should show me.
.schema 应该能展示给我。
OK, it's actually a very simple database, a registrants table with one,
好的，它实际上是一个非常简单的数据库，一个名为 registrants 的表，它包含一个
two, three columns, an ID for a unique identifier,
两个，三个列，一个用于唯一标识的 ID，
a primary key, the name of the person, and the sport
一个主键，该人的姓名，以及参加的运动
for which they're registering.
他们注册的项目。
And, presumably, the ID will be automatically incremented for me.
并且，据推测，ID 会自动为我递增。
So let me exit out of that.
所以让我退出。
Go back to app.py.
回到 app.py。
And this line 8 here is just giving me access to that SQLite database.
而这第 8 行只是让我访问了那个 SQLite 数据库。
And recall that the three slashes are appropriate.
回想一下，这三个斜杠是合适的。
It's not a typo relative to something like a URL.
它与类似 URL 的东西相比不是一个拼写错误。
Here is my three sports that I want to support.
这里是我想要支持的三项运动。
Looks like my index route is pretty much the same.
看起来我的索引路由与之前基本相同。
So nothing new there.
所以那里没有新东西。
In fact, I'm using that same lesson as before
事实上，我正在使用与之前相同的课程
in passing in the whole sports list.
传递整个运动列表。
Notice that, OK, this is interesting.
请注意，好的，这很有趣。
Deregister, this version is going to let users sort of bow out of a sport
注销，这个版本将允许用户退出某项运动
as tends to happen over the course of a semester.
就像在一个学期中经常发生的那样。
But we'll come back to that.
但我们会回到这个话题。
But let's look at register now.
但现在让我们看看 register。
register is almost the same even though I do have some comments here.
register 与之前几乎相同，尽管我在这里有一些注释。
We're making sure to validate the form.
我们确保验证表单。
But this is where it gets interesting.
但这里就变得有趣了。
I'm now inserting rows into the database to register these registrants.
我现在正在将行插入数据库以注册这些注册者。
Notice that I'm using CS50's library to insert into the registrants table
请注意，我正在使用 CS50 的库将数据插入 registrants 表
into these two columns name and sport, these two values.
到这两个列 name 和 sport 中，这两个值。
And I'm being very careful to use question marks to escape the user's
而且我非常谨慎地使用问号来转义用户的
input to avoid injection attacks.
输入，以避免注入攻击。
And then I just redirect the user.
然后我只需重定向用户。
But what's going to be interesting about this version is this too,
但这个版本有趣的地方还在于，
/registrants no longer just uses Jinja and iterates over a global variable.
/registrants 不再仅仅使用 Jinja 并且遍历全局变量。
In this version, we're selecting all of the registrants
在这个版本中，我们正在选择所有注册者
and getting back a list of dictionaries.
并将它们作为字典列表返回。
And then we're passing that list of dictionaries
然后我们将这个字典列表
into the Jinja template called registrants.html.
传递给名为 registrants.html 的 Jinja 模板。
So, just to make clear what's going on there,
所以，为了清楚地说明那里发生了什么，
let me open up templates and registrants.html.
让我打开模板和 registrants.html。
It's almost the same as before.
它与之前几乎相同。
Notice that I'm using the dot notation this time, which Jinja also supports.
请注意，我这次使用了点表示法，Jinja 也支持它。
And it's almost always the same as the square bracket notation.
而且它几乎总是与方括号表示法相同。
So you'll see both in documentation online.
所以你将在网上的文档中看到这两种表示法。
But notice that I have a third column in the registrants table
但请注意，我在 registrants 表中有一个第三列
that's a little interesting.
有点意思。
And this will be the final lesson for froshims.
而这将是 froshims 的最后一课。
A button via which people can deregister themselves, like a bow out of froshims.
一个按钮，人们可以通过它注销自己，就像退出 froshims 一样。
So let's do this.
所以让我们这样做。
Open the terminal.
打开终端。
Let's do flask run in version 5 of this here.
让我们在版本 5 中运行 flask run。
Let me go into my other tab, close the Developer Tools, go to the /route,
让我进入另一个选项卡，关闭开发者工具，进入 /route，
and I have a form quite like before.
我有一个与之前非常相似的表单。
But now, when I register, David for soccer and click
但现在，当我注册 David 参加足球并点击
Register, notice that it's ugly UI.
注册，请注意它是一个丑陋的 UI。
But there's a button next to David to deregister themselves.
但 David 旁边有一个按钮可以让他们注销自己。
Let's go back to slash.
让我们回到斜杠。
Let me also register Carter, for instance, for basketball and so forth.
让我注册 Carter，例如，参加篮球等等。
There's now two buttons.
现在有两个按钮了。
This, now, is what really ties together our discussion of SQL
现在，这真正将我们对 SQL 的讨论
and primary keys with the world of the web.
和主键与网络世界联系在一起。
Suppose that there were two Davids in the class, which there surely are,
假设课堂上有两个 David，这肯定有，
two Carters, two Yulias, two of any names.
两个 Carter，两个 Yulia，以及两个任何名字的人。
We clearly can't rely on first names alone
我们显然不能仅仅依靠名字
to uniquely identify humans in a room like this.
来唯一识别像这样的房间里的人。
So we probably should use opaque identifiers,
因此我们可能应该使用不透明的标识符，
that is, those numbers, 1, 2, 3.
也就是说，那些数字，1、2、3。
Indeed, if I go into VS Code--
实际上，如果我进入 VS Code -
let me open another terminal and make it bigger.
让我打开另一个终端，并将其放大。
And, in my src9 froshims version 5, let me run sqlite3 of froshims.db.
在我的 src9 froshims 版本 5 中，让我运行 froshims.db 的 sqlite3。
And, sure enough, if I do SELECT * FROM registrants; I'll see the two of us
而且，果然，如果我执行 SELECT * FROM registrants；我会看到我们俩
thus far.
到目前为止。
And we've indeed been automatically-- been
并且我们实际上已经自动地 - 被
assigned an auto-incrementing primary key, 1, 2, respectively.
分配了自动递增的主键，分别是 1 和 2。
That's useful now in the web especially or user interfaces in general.
这在网络中尤其有用，或者在一般的用户界面中也是如此。
If I view this page as source, here in my browser,
如果我将此页面视为源代码，在我的浏览器中，
notice that both David and Carter have their own form in a third td
请注意，David 和 Carter 都在第三个 td 中有自己的表单
element next to them.
元素旁边。
And that's what gives us this.
这就是给我们这个的原因。
But notice that form, even though it's an ugly UI,
但请注意那个表单，即使它是一个丑陋的 UI，
is a form that will post to a /deregister route a hidden input,
是一个会将一个隐藏的输入发布到 /deregister 路由的表单，
the name of which is ID to match the primary key column,
它的名称是 ID，与主键列匹配，
the value of which is 1 for me and 2 for Carter.
它的值为 1（对我）和 2（对 Carter）。
So this is how you stitch together a browser and a server.
所以，这就是将浏览器和服务器连接起来的方式。